<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Statement on Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Statement on Robert Howton</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Robert Howton</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Project</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/research/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/research/book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;_aristotle-on-perceptual-discrimination_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aristotle on Perceptual Discrimination&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &amp;ldquo;Aristotle on Why the Senses Discriminate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Aristotle on the End of an Organism&#39;s Nature&amp;rdquo; are accepted for publication, I plan to write a book manuscript that draws together both major topics of my research. The book, &lt;em&gt;Aristotle on Perceptual Discrimination&lt;/em&gt;, will be the first dedicated study of Aristotle&#39;s thesis that the senses are discriminative capacities of soul. While this thesis has received greater attention from commentators in recent years, it has for the most part been considered in isolation from its context in the explanatory project of the Aristotelian life sciences and read instead as part of an attempt to explain the character of ordinary perceptual experience. I argue that this is a mistake. For Aristotle, the significance of the thesis that the senses are discriminative capacities concerns precisely the teleological role of sense perception in animal life. To the question, why do animals perceive in the ways they do?, Aristotle has a single, univocal answer: because the senses are &lt;em&gt;discriminative&lt;/em&gt; capacities. By this, Aristotle means that the senses belong to the animals that have them because &lt;em&gt;discriminating&lt;/em&gt; by means of those senses promotes the achievement of the ends those animals naturally pursue. Understanding Aristotle&#39;s thesis that the senses discriminate therefore requires understanding how Aristotle thinks sensory discrimination contributes to goals that structure animal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book defends a novel answer to this question. For Aristotle, discriminating a sensible quality by means of the sense that perceives it is a way of &lt;em&gt;knowing&lt;/em&gt; that quality&amp;mdash;a state Aristotle understands as one in which the perceiver is presented with the cause of a perceptual experience &lt;em&gt;as that cause essentially is&lt;/em&gt;. For this reason, Aristotle&#39;s case for the thesis that the senses are discriminative capacities is a case for regarding perception as a kind of &lt;em&gt;knowledge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I present Aristotle&#39;s case for perceptual discrimination as a response to two historical challenges, &lt;em&gt;Democritean Eliminativism&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Platonic Intellectualism&lt;/em&gt;. According to Democritean Eliminativism, sensible qualities such as colors and flavors cannot be objects of knowledge because they are not genuine &lt;em&gt;causes&lt;/em&gt; but rather effects on a perceiver&amp;mdash;a view that in Aristotle&#39;s estimation amounts to a denial that sensible qualities &lt;em&gt;exist&lt;/em&gt;. According to Platonic Intellectualism, even if the senses put the perceiver in touch with genuine causes, perception of sensible qualities cannot amount to &lt;em&gt;knowledge&lt;/em&gt; of these qualities, since only the soul &lt;em&gt;by itself&lt;/em&gt; can &amp;ldquo;discriminate&amp;rdquo; the being of the qualities perceived by the senses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1-against-democritean-eliminativism&#34;&gt;Part 1: Against Democritean Eliminativism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Against Democritean Eliminativism, Aristotle defends a thoroughly realist and objectivist conception of sensible qualities. On his view, colors, flavors, and other sensible qualities are identical to the causal, physical features of sensible bodies that enable them to produce experiences of those qualities in us. &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/strong&gt; argues that this conception of sensible &lt;em&gt;qualities&lt;/em&gt; should be distinguished from Aristotle&#39;s discussion in &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; of sensible &lt;em&gt;objects&lt;/em&gt;, which are perceiver-dependent in a way in which sensible qualities are not. &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/strong&gt; defends an interpretation of Aristotle&#39;s account of the essence of sensible qualities in &lt;em&gt;De Sensu&lt;/em&gt;. I argue that Aristotle defends a physicalist conception of sensible qualities. But unlike modern physicalists, Aristotle denies that there is a necessary contrast between the way a perceptual quality appears in experience and the way it essentially is. Since a perceptual quality is “mixture &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; motion,” it can appear in experience as the perceiver-independent property it essentially is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-against-platonic-intellectualism&#34;&gt;Part 2: Against Platonic Intellectualism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapters 3&amp;ndash;5 detail Aristotle&#39;s response to Platonic Intellectualism. As Aristotle sees it, the challenge is to show that the senses themselves can discriminate the sensible qualities they perceive. I argue that Aristotle&#39;s account of the sensory capacities of the soul are designed in part to meet this challenge. &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/strong&gt; considers Aristotle&#39;s view that the senses are like &amp;ldquo;ratios&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;mean states&amp;rdquo; of the qualities they perceive, a claim that forms the basis of an argument demonstrating that the senses discriminate. On the interpretation I provide, the senses are mean states because each is the form and final cause of an organ that, &lt;em&gt;qua&lt;/em&gt; organ of that sense, instantiates the objective mean of the scale of qualities that sense perceives. This interpretation sets up a question about the nature of perceptual affection&amp;mdash;one that has received abundant attention from scholars in recent decades. &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/strong&gt; addresses this question with a novel proposal. Perceptual affection is neither a literal alteration of the sense organ nor a purely formal or &amp;ldquo;spiritual&amp;rdquo; change. It is not a change at all, but an affection whose nature is exhausted by the activity of a sensible quality and excludes any alteration of the organ&amp;mdash;a process Aristotle in another context compares to getting a sunburn or growing red from embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing on this conception of the sensory mean state, &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5&lt;/strong&gt; presents Aristotle&#39;s argument demonstrating that the senses discriminate. The demonstration is initially obscure, but Aristotle&#39;s reasoning is illuminated by an analogy with his celebrated doctrine of the ethical mean. Because virtue is a mean state, vicious actions and emotions appear to the virtuous person as what they essentially are, namely excessive or deficient. Similarly, because each sense is a mean state, the qualities it perceives appear to it as what they essentially are, namely light or dark, sweet or bitter, or more generally as occupying the objective position on the quality scale that defines each as the quality it is. For a sense to “discriminate” a perceptual quality, then, is for that quality to appear to the &lt;em&gt;sensory&lt;/em&gt; mean state as what it essentially is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-the-significance-of-aristotles-perceptual-epistemology&#34;&gt;Part 3: The Significance of Aristotle&#39;s Perceptual Epistemology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of the book explores the psychological, epistemological, and historical consequences of this conception of perceptual discrimination. &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6&lt;/strong&gt; considers the unity of the senses in numerically one and the same perceptual capacity and the consequent ability of perceivers both to make discriminations across sensory modalities and to perceive the unity of sensible qualities in a single sensible body. While Aristotle&#39;s much-discussed attempts to account for these advanced forms of perceptual discrimination may fail, I argue that they provide indirect support for the present interpretation of &lt;em&gt;sensory&lt;/em&gt; discrimination. For the theoretical limitations that seem to prevent Aristotle from providing a satisfactory account of these forms of perceptual discrimination stem from an conception of the senses that, I argue, Aristotle takes to be central to his demonstrative account of sensory discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/strong&gt; considers Aristotle&#39;s claim that perception is a &lt;em&gt;gnôsis tis&lt;/em&gt;, a mode of &amp;ldquo;cognition&amp;rdquo; or knowledge. While this claim has led many commentators to conclude that Aristotle has an &amp;ldquo;implicitly graded&amp;rdquo; notion of cognition, on the present interpretation perception turns out to be a full-fledged cognitive capacity, standing in relation to sensible qualities as scientific knowledge, craft knowledge, and &lt;em&gt;nous&lt;/em&gt; do to their respective objects. In support of this reading, I consider Aristotle&#39;s teleological explanations of sense perception in non-rational animals in &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;De Sensu&lt;/em&gt;, drawing on Aristotle&#39;s conception of soul as a &amp;ldquo;complex activity&amp;rdquo; organized in the pursuit of a single, teleologically primary end. I also consider the role of perception in scientific inquiry in the &lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt;, arguing that the &amp;ldquo;prior knowledge&amp;rdquo; provided by perception from which rational perceivers come to know the first principles of a science consists in knowledge of the causes of particular sensory experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8&lt;/strong&gt; provides a historical epilogue to the foregoing discussion of Aristotle&#39;s theory of perceptual discrimination. I argue that, in responding to Democritean Eliminativism and Platonic Intellectualism, Aristotle sees himself as reviving a Protagorean conception of perception as a measure or &amp;ldquo;criterion&amp;rdquo; for objects&amp;rsquo; possession of sensible qualities, although one which respects a thoroughly objective and realist ontology. Understanding Aristotle&#39;s perceptual epistemology in this way, I argue, brings it into close contact with next-generation debates over whether the senses or our sensory impressions can serve as &amp;ldquo;criteria of truth,&amp;rdquo; a result that promises to shed new light on the development of Hellenistic epistemology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/research/papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-aristotles-theory-of-perceptual-discrimination&#34;&gt;On Aristotle&#39;s Theory of Perceptual Discrimination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;perception-and-hypothetical-necessity-in-_posterior-analytics_-219&#34;&gt;Perception and Hypothetical Necessity in &lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 2.19&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 2.19, Aristotle argues that knowledge of the first principles of a demonstrative science is acquired from the &amp;ldquo;innate discriminative capacity&amp;rdquo; we call &lt;em&gt;perception&lt;/em&gt;. On a straightforward reading, his argument is conspicuously bad, failing specifically to rule out a rival innatist position that would have appeared viable both in his view and in that of his likely opponents. My aim in this paper is to show that Aristotle can be credited with a more satisfactory and, by his lights, cogent argument if we read it as an appeal to a distinctively natural scientific form of explanation, what Aristotle sometimes calls &amp;ldquo;hypothetical necessity.&amp;rdquo; In doing so, however, I argue that we must also come to see that Aristotle&#39;s conception of the role of perception in coming to know first principles is rooted in substantive and controversial psychological theses that find support, not in the foregoing chapters of the &lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt;, but in natural scientific works like &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Parva Naturalia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Revise &amp;amp; Resubmit&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aristotle-on-why-the-senses-discriminate&#34;&gt;Aristotle on Why the Senses Discriminate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle regards the senses as &amp;ldquo;discriminative&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;kritikê&lt;/em&gt;), capacities not only to be affected by and perceive sensible qualities, but also to &amp;ldquo;discriminate and cognize something that is.&amp;rdquo; Commentators since antiquity have tended to make two assumptions about the sensory capacity to discriminate: first that it is a capacity the senses have &lt;em&gt;essentially&lt;/em&gt;, and second that its exercise results in a certain sort of &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; as of the difference between sensible qualities or their unity in a sensible body. I argue that both assumptions are mistaken. First, I argue that the capacity to discriminate is not essential but a scientifically knowable attribute of the senses, and that in &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; Aristotle offers two arguments explaining why the senses discriminate, one final causal and one formal causal. Second, I argue that the capacity these arguments attribute to the senses is epistemically far richer than commentators have supposed: the capacity to become aware of the mind-independent features of sensible bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Nearing completion, will be under review by 2/2020&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mixture-and-motion-aristotle-on-the-nature-of-sensible-qualities&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mixture and Motion&amp;rdquo;: Aristotle on the Nature of Sensible Qualities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle identifies colors, sounds, flavors, and other sensible qualities with the physical properties that cause us to experience those qualities. However, unlike modern &amp;ldquo;physicalist&amp;rdquo; theories of sensible qualities, Aristotle does not draw a distinction between how we experience a quality and how that quality essentially is. I argue that this unique and puzzling feature of Aristotle&#39;s physicalism stems from a commitment to the view that a sensible quality is an abstract, mathematical form present in its actual as well as its potential instances, and I show that this view enables him to avoid some prominent objections to physicalist theories of sensible qualities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Promised to Editor, Preliminary Draft&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sensible-qualities-sensible-objects-and-aristotles-realism&#34;&gt;Sensible Qualities, Sensible Objects, and Aristotle&#39;s Realism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle seems to think that objects for the most part have the colors, sounds, odors, and flavors we experience them as having, irrespective of whether they are experienced as having them. But for many commentators his commitment to this realist picture is importantly qualified. In their view, Aristotle concedes that colors, sounds, and other sensible qualities are &lt;em&gt;in actuality&lt;/em&gt; dependent on perceivers, so that a world without perceivers would be a world in which nothing is colored or sounding in the fullest sense. I argue that qualified realist views fail to distinguish two essentially distinct potentialities of material bodies, namely that which makes the body sensibly &lt;em&gt;qualified&lt;/em&gt; (colored or sounding) and that which makes it &lt;em&gt;sensible&lt;/em&gt; (visible or audible). Once we draw this distinction, we can see that Aristotle consistently&amp;mdash;both in &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; and elsewhere&amp;mdash;maintains an unqualified realism about sensible qualities, according to which a world without perceivers could be just as colorful, sonorous, and flavorful as ours is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Preliminary Draft&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-soul-as-a-complex-activity-in-aristotles-natural-science&#34;&gt;On Soul as a &amp;ldquo;Complex Activity&amp;rdquo; in Aristotle&#39;s Natural Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aristotle-on-the-end-of-an-organisms-nature&#34;&gt;Aristotle on the End of an Organism&#39;s Nature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In at least four passages of the corpus, Aristotle appeals to what we might term the &amp;ldquo;natural end&amp;rdquo; of an organism. The notion is evidently significant for Aristotle&#39;s approach to the life sciences, appearing decisively in explanations of phenomena such as animal perception and the observable order of embryonic development. However, both the notion and its explanatory role have been neglected in recent studies of Aristotle&#39;s natural teleology. This paper develops an interpretation of the natural end of an organism and its explanatory role in the Aristotelian life sciences, in an effort to prepare the way for a full appreciation of this important feature of Aristotle&#39;s natural teleology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the interpretation I defend, the natural end of an organism is the realization of the natural activity for whose sake that organism possesses and engages in each of the activities it is naturally capable of engaging in. So understood, the notion of an organism&#39;s natural end is bound intimately to a conception of organic life, and hence of the soul, as a complex of activities unified in the pursuit of a single, teleologically primary activity. This &amp;ldquo;complex activity model&amp;rdquo; of soul originates in &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt;, but its explanatory implications reach to Aristotle&#39;s account of organic development and morphology, accounting in particular for the developmental priority the parts of the animal body through the use of which the animal achieves the &amp;ldquo;goal that is the function of its nature.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In Progress&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;material-nature-in-aristotles-_parts-of-animals_&#34;&gt;Material Nature in Aristotle&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Parts of Animals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biological kinds are thought to pose a special problem for Aristotle&#39;s approach to explanation. The problem is that some physiological attributes naturally belonging to living things seem not to be explained by their soul&amp;mdash;their form and essence&amp;mdash;but by their matter. I argue that the problem is only apparent, and that we can see the soul as the basis of even these explanations if we take into account Aristotle&#39;s claim in &lt;em&gt;Parts of Animals&lt;/em&gt; 1.5 (645b28&amp;ndash;646a2) that the organic parts of a living body stand in teleological relations that mirror those of the psychic activities for which they are instruments. On the basis of this claim, I argue that the soul accounts for a living thing&#39;s physiological attributes as both an efficient cause of its coming to be and the final cause of its being. I support this interpretation by showing that the parallel relations of teleological priority among psychic capacities and their material organs explain, first of all, the order in which the parts of the animal body are said to develop in &lt;em&gt;Generation of Animals&lt;/em&gt;, and second, Aristotle&#39;s appeal to &amp;ldquo;material nature&amp;rdquo; in some controversial passages of &lt;em&gt;Parts of Animals&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Projected&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-other-topics-in-aristotles-psychology&#34;&gt;On Other Topics in Aristotle&#39;s Psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hearing-speech-incidentally-an-aristotelian-distinction-concerning-perceptual-content&#34;&gt;Hearing Speech Incidentally: An Aristotelian Distinction Concerning Perceptual Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a familiar difference between the experience of hearing a language one understands and the experience of hearing a language one doesn&#39;t understand. But theorists disagree on how this contrast is reflected in the &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; of these auditory experiences. Conservative approaches take the difference to concern non-semantic properties of the linguistic utterance, including low-level properties (such as pitch and timbre) as well as language-specific properties (such as being this or that phoneme). Liberal approaches, by contrast, take the difference also to concern whether the subject hears, or fails to hear, the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of the relevant utterance. I argue for a moderate approach, taking my point of departure from the Aristotelian idea that the meaning of a linguistic utterance is audible, but only &amp;ldquo;incidentally&amp;rdquo; so. I argue that this approach avoids the difficulties facing both the conservative and liberal approaches, and moreover provides a model for a broadly speaking Aristotelian theory of perceptual content that warrants serious consideration in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Preliminary Draft&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aristotle-on-why-animals-have-_phantasia_&#34;&gt;Aristotle on Why Animals Have &lt;em&gt;Phantasia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle gives contradictory answers to the question whether all animals have &lt;em&gt;phantasia&lt;/em&gt; (imagination). But while some commentators have claimed that Aristotle ultimately defends a positive or negative answer to the question, I argue that his ambivalence is well-motivated. Aristotle is pulled in different directions because he attributes two distinct roles to &lt;em&gt;phantasia&lt;/em&gt;. In all animals it is responsible for the phenomenal character of experience, but it also serves as a representational faculty in the cognitively more sophisticated ones. I draw two morals from this conclusion: first, and against other recent interpretations, that &lt;em&gt;phantasia&lt;/em&gt; is primarily the faculty responsible for providing the experiential, qualitative aspects of cognitive episodes; second, and more speculatively, that for Aristotle the representational content of an experience supervenes on its phenomenal character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Status:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Preliminary Draft&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
