<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching Dossier | Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching Dossier</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Robert Howton</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Teaching Dossier</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas of Teaching Competence</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/competence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/competence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;primary-areas-of-teaching-competence&#34;&gt;Primary Areas of Teaching Competence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ancient Greek Philosophy, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Ancient Greek Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hellenic Philosophy: the Presocratics, Socrates, Plato, Aristotle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hellenistic Philosophy: Epicureanism, Stoicism, Academic and Pyrrhonian Skepticism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philosophy of Mind, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to the Philosophy of Mind, thematic or historical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thematic or historical surveys on several topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mind-Body Problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perception&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems of Consciousness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intentionality and Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singular Thought, Reference, and Demonstration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secondary-areas-of-teaching-competence&#34;&gt;Secondary Areas of Teaching Competence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epistemology, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Epistemology, thematic or historical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thematic or historical surveys on several topics, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puzzles of Knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justification&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skepticism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early Modern Philosophy, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Early Modern Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rationalism: Descartes, Spinoza, Leibniz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empiricism: Locke, Berkeley, Hume&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medieval Philosophy, including the early Christian, Latin, Byzantine, and Islamic traditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logic, introductory and intermediate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Statement</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching at the University of Toronto (located in the heart of a richly
multicultural city), the University of Pittsburgh (with its large and
international student body), and Koç University (where almost none of
the students share my linguistic or cultural upbringing) has given me
experience with students from a wide variety of cultural, linguistic,
and educational backgrounds and of different philosophical abilities. In
my view, engaging with such a diversity of perspectives is one of the
chief pleasures of teaching philosophy. But I also believe that a
diverse student body places special responsibilities on a teacher of
philosophy, who must be sensitive to the different needs of students as
they approach philosophical texts, aware of the cultural presuppositions
of major philosophical figures that may not be shared by all students,
and willing to confront the perception that philosophy is a devotion
exclusive to affluent white men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am committed to facilitating fruitful engagement with philosophical
texts for students of all cultural, linguistic, and educational
backgrounds, and in my teaching I take measures to promote every
student&amp;rsquo;s interest and success in her philosophical education. First, I
make an effort to maximize the diversity of my syllabi in courses on the
history of philosophy as well as on contemporary topics. While this may
seem harder to do in the history of philosophy, I have found success
incorporating women philosophers and philosophers of color in developing
and teaching syllabi for ancient, medieval, and modern philosophy. In
the medieval and modern periods we are fortunate to have correspondence
of some of those periods&amp;rsquo; major figures&amp;mdash;including Abelard, Descartes,
Leibniz, and Locke&amp;mdash;with lesser-known women philosophers, including
Héloïse, Elizabeth of Bohemia, and Damaris Masham. I think these
correspondence are valuable teaching tools and I make them a central
feature of my introductory course on modern philosophy. The ancient
period is more difficult, in particular since almost nothing survives
from women intellectuals of that period. However, in my teaching I try
to stress the significance of medieval Arabic and North African
philosophers (who are also worthy of study in their own right) on the
transmission and interpretation of ancient philosophers, especially
Aristotle, as well the important role that contemporary women
philosophers and philosophers of color have played in advancing our
understanding of ancient philosophical texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe diversifying syllabi benefits students in at least two ways.
First, it demonstrates the variety of perspectives that have shaped and
continue to shape the discipline. Second, it exposes students to
philosophical themes in ways that may be more compelling and relevant to
their experience. For instance, the unit on metaphysics in my
introduction to philosophy course frames issues concerning essence and
human nature in terms of contemporary debates about the relationship
between our biological nature as human beings and other aspects of our
respective identities, including race and disability. By presenting
fundamental metaphysical questions through the work of minority
philosophers like Charles Mills and Elizabeth Barnes, I aim to show
students that even abstract philosophical questions can bear on issues
relevant to their own lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second measure I take, especially when teaching the history of
philosophy, is to ensure that all students are provided with the
historical and cultural context necessary for understanding course
material. The importance of this practice was impressed on me several
years ago, when, as a TA for a course on early medieval philosophy, an
international student asked me to explain what is distinctive about the
Christian God. What surprised me about the question was that I had
assumed&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;wrongly&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;that my students shared the same broad familiarity
with the religious context of medieval Christian philosophers that I
received from my own upbringing. From then on, I have striven to reflect
critically on the assumptions I bring to my presentation of especially
classical philosophical texts, and as far as possible to make those
assumptions explicit for the benefit of those who do not share my
cultural background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I take measures in student evaluation to counteract my own
implicit biases and to encourage the success of students who, for
various reasons, struggle with English academic prose. In general, I
rely on anonymous grading as much as possible, and I encourage students
who would benefit from alternative forms of evaluation to work with me
to develop a suitable approach to their assessment, whether it involves
verbal testing by one-on-one discussion with me, take home reports, or
other means. However, one form of evaluation I&amp;rsquo;ve insisted on is
writing. In many cases, I think it is a disservice to students not to
use a philosophy course as a vehicle for improving skills as important
as prose composition. However, I also recognize that some students have
greater educational deficits to overcome in their writing than others. I
have various ways of helping these students improve their writing and
succeed in my courses, including encourage them to seek help from me in
drafting papers, taking time to correct grammar in grading drafts, and
(when necessary) exercising lenience in penalizing poor grammar to
encourage students to express their philosophical ideas to the best of
their ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more I can do to encourage the interest and success in
philosophy of a diverse student body, and I am interested in learning
and testing new methods for doing so. I see philosophy as a &amp;ldquo;big tent&amp;rdquo;
discipline, one that can and ought to welcome a diversity of
perspectives. As a white, cisgender male, I believe my role in advancing
this conception of the discipline is to give a platform for voices
different from my own to make their contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/effectiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/effectiveness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ![Aristotle Teaching](aristotleteaching.jpg) --&gt;
&lt;!-- 














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;st-catherine-disputing-with-scholars-by-masolino-da-panicale.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;A caption&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;st-catherine-disputing-with-scholars-by-masolino-da-panicale.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    A caption
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section provides evidence for my effectiveness in teaching drawn from student evaluations. Click the link for the relevant semester to view an overview of quantitative and qualitative student feedback from the courses given that semester, as well as links to complete raw data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2016fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2016fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-0460-introduction-to-philosophy-of-mind&#34;&gt;PHIL 0460: Introduction to Philosophy of Mind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2016%20Fall%20-%20PHIL%200460%20-%20Quantitative%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Quantitative Data
&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2016%20Fall%20-%20PHIL%200460%20-%20Qualitative%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Qualitative Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor presented the course in an organized manner.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor stimulated my thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor evaluated my work fairly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor made good use of examples to clarify concepts.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.54&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.67&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor maintained a good learning environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was accessible to students.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Express your judgment of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s overall teaching effectiveness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.78&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    53 respondents totaling 47% of registered students; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Robbie is friendly and shows great passion for the subject. He is not
alienating, and has only increased my passion for philosophy. A
remarkable professor. Also, amazingly lively for a 9 AM class.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He was very approachable and accessible. He is a very good
professor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The lectures were very organized and I loved that the lecture notes
were always posted on CourseWeb in advance so that I could focus more
on what Dr. Howton was saying while adding extra notes I felt I
needed&lt;/strong&gt;. He seems very passionate about what he does and provides
really good examples to clarify sometimes confusing topics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He commanded his lectures extremely well. He spoke strongly and
clearly. He never seemed to rush through his notes which covered the
material so well that it almost entirely eliminated the need for
references beyond the readings. And the readings themselves charted an
incredibly ordered and logical coarse [sic] through out the entire
semester such that, now at the end, everything we&amp;rsquo;ve learned has led
seamlessly from one place to the next, culminating in the most
interesting and complex material.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He was never hard to approach and always polite and patient when
explaining concepts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2017fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2017fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-0080-introduction-to-philosophical-problems&#34;&gt;PHIL 0080: Introduction to Philosophical Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2017%20Fall%20-%20PHIL%200080%20-%20Combined%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor created an atmosphere that kept me engaged in course content.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.83&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was prepared for class.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor treated students with respect.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;84&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was available to me (in-person, electronically, or both).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor evaluated my work fairly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;68&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor provided feedback that was helpful to me.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I learned a lot from this course.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Total enrollment 115; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an air of egalitarianism, and Robbie is clearly enthusiastic about the subject to the point of it being infectious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;liked how the powerpoint helped to guide my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked how Robbie provided us with the slides before lecture so we could take notes directly on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the material was conveniently organized and located on courseweb [= Blackboard], negating the need to purchase materials or flip through pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very engaging and handled touchy topics very gracefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system of prep materials before the content and options to learn more after we covered that material in lecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the outside [= &amp;ldquo;Prep&amp;rdquo;] material we reviewed before class, it was very relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning from videos and podcasts outside of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked how there were different examples and resources provided for each topic in order to better our understanding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciated how easy it was to ask questions and discuss concepts during lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robbie is obviously really smart. He lets students asks questions and answers them thoroughly. The lecture slides were very organized and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2018fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2018fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-403-topics-in-ancient-philosophy-aristotles-psychology&#34;&gt;PHIL 403: Topics in Ancient Philosophy: Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2018%20Fall%20-%20PHIL%20403%20-%20Combined%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;**% Resp.**&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s preparedness for classes was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.71&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s ability to communicate and explain effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s willingness to provide help when needed was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.57&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructors use of class time effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructors enthusiasm was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.71&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of instructor&amp;rsquo;s concern for students&amp;rsquo; learning and progress was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s attitude towards students was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.71&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The amount of knowledge gained from the course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The materials used in the course were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In terms of helping me learn the subject matter, the teaching methods were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The methods used to measure learning were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The course&amp;rsquo;s organization was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s content knowledge was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.71&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the instructor was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.67&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;60%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;60%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    7-point scale ranging from +3 [extremely good] to -3 [extremely poor]; total enrollment: 10 students.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No qualitative feedback received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hums-132-illusions-when-appearances-deceive&#34;&gt;HUMS 132: Illusions: When Appearances Deceive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2018%20Fall%20-%20HUMS%20132%20-%20Combined%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback-1&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;**% Resp.**&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s preparedness for classes was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s ability to communicate and explain effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s willingness to provide help when needed was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructors use of class time effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructors enthusiasm was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of instructor&amp;rsquo;s concern for students&amp;rsquo; learning and progress was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s attitude towards students was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The amount of knowledge gained from the course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The materials used in the course were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.97&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In terms of helping me learn the subject matter, the teaching methods were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The methods used to measure learning were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The course&amp;rsquo;s organization was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.38&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s content knowledge was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the instructor was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.64&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    7-point scale ranging from +3 [extremely good] to -3 [extremely poor]; total enrollment: 40 students.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback-1&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;He is a great teacher. He really changed my opinion on philosophy for the better.&lt;/strong&gt; I enjoyed being in his class.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dr. Howton this year was one of the greatest teachers that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. I&amp;rsquo;ve gained a lot of knowledge and new point of views [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] from his teaching skills.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The teacher was really patient towards every question that students have. The slides shown were very useful for the course and for exams. Whenever I had an issue, he was very kind and accurate with helping in term papers and essays.&lt;/strong&gt; The only disadvantage was that the texts were really long and in the it felt boring to go till the end of the text.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I took this course by pure chance. I&amp;rsquo;m extremely glad that I did. &lt;strong&gt;I learned so much, I could never thank Robbie enough. Koç University is lucky to have a person like him, and I am very lucky to have been enrolled in his class.&lt;/strong&gt; I really wish more proffessors [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] were like him. Sincerely, thank you Robbie. You have touched my mind and helped me answer some questions. &lt;strong&gt;The relation between real life and the class material was amazing.&lt;/strong&gt; I hope to see you again!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Best instructor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2016spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2016spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-1440-philosophy-of-mind&#34;&gt;PHIL 1440: Philosophy of Mind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2016%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%201440%20-%20Combined%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor presented the course in an organized manner.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor stimulated my thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor evaluated my work fairly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor made good use of examples to clarify concepts.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor maintained a good learning environment.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was accessible to students.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Express your judgment of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s overall teaching effectiveness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.55&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    11 respondents totaling 79% of registered students; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Being the lead discussant was beneficial to me because it forced me
to really engage with the material and understand how it fit together
with other ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Giving out lecture notes for every unit was a major help for getting
the major points of each lecture and consolidating the material in a
very organized manner. Also he heavily encouraged sending him drafts
of all of our writing so he can give us comments and help us improve
the piece before turning it in. He gave great examples, and was very
effective at explaining difficult material. He also made himself
available outside of office hours of [sic] need be.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There was an appropriate balance between maintaining a constructive
learning environment, while still ensuring that everyone felt
comfortable to speak their mind and ask questions. The discussion
matched with the lectures was engaging and beneficial. Also, the
information was organized in a chronological way so I could really see
how all the different theories of mind related to each other and built
off ones from the past.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;My reading, reasoning, and writing skills were definitely improved
throughout the course.&lt;/strong&gt; I got a more in depth look at a branch of
philosophy which I have only had a small understanding prior to this
course. &lt;strong&gt;I also became familiar with more technical philosophical
terms, which will be very helpful for the rest of my education, and
reading philosophy on my own.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2017spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2017spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-1040-aristotle&#34;&gt;PHIL 1040: Aristotle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2017%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%201040%20-%20Quantitative%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Quantitative Data
&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2017%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%201040%20-%20Qualitative%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Qualitative Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor presented the course in an organized manner.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor stimulated my thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was enthusiastic about teaching the course.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor maintained an environment where students felt comfortable participating.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor maintained an environment where students felt comfortable seeking assistance.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor provided helpful feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;5.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Assignments contributed to my understanding of the subject.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Express your judgment of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s overall teaching effectiveness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    11 respondents totaling 64.71% of registered students; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Each lecture was enthusiastically and clearly expressed. &lt;strong&gt;One thing
I found very helpful was the &amp;lsquo;scribe sheets&amp;rsquo; made by students as an
assignment then uploaded as study guides. This provided a great way to
review old material, make sure nothing was missed, and to catch up on
a class if one was unable to make it. Though the scribe sheets were
made by us he guided us through the process and gave corrections and
supplementations for each one before it was uploaded.&lt;/strong&gt; Additionally,
I found the presentations a helpful way to be exposed to material that
was more advanced and available for interpretation. His selection of
the articles was helpful in guiding that exposure&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lectures were excellent, engaging, and immensely detailed. So much
information was presented during each class meeting, and yet Professor
Howton&amp;rsquo;s lectures flowed so well and were so effective at reinforcing
new information as it was introduced that it never felt overwhelming.
Required homework for each class meeting was more demanding than
expected, but meant that comprehension of what was being discussed was
far better (as the assignments required high attentiveness towards
readings). &lt;strong&gt;Questions were answered phenomenally well in class.
Seemed to genuinely care about students, both with regard to the
quality of the learning process and to the students themselves.&lt;/strong&gt;
Exams were occasionally tough but always fair, and constructive
feedback offered for all assignments was always excellent. Overall,
fantastic experience.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Your lectures are the most stimulating and entertaining of any
course I have ever taken outside of my major.&lt;/strong&gt; I loved going to
lecture. It was the highlight of my week. &lt;strong&gt;Also I really liked the
reading questions system. It ensured that I did the readings every
week and that I went to lecture. I really don&amp;rsquo;t think I would have
been successful in this course without that system.&lt;/strong&gt; It also was nice
because it provided a lot of opportunity for points that would not
have been possible otherwise. Thank you for a fantastic semester!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am not sure what Robert could do to improve. &lt;strong&gt;I am not sure how
long Robert has been lecturing, I presume that it cannot be especially
long based on how old he looks; nevertheless, he provided perhaps the
most exceptional class experience I have ever had.&lt;/strong&gt; The greatness of
Aristotle does not need comment but Robert enhanced the material in
every way. Often times during the semester, when Robert started
preaching the gospel, I could not help moving and dancing in my seat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-0450-theories-of-knowledge--reality&#34;&gt;PHIL 0450: Theories of Knowledge &amp;amp; Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2017%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%200450%20-%20Quantitative%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Quantitative Data
&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2017%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%200450%20-%20Qualitative%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Qualitative Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback-1&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor presented the course in an organized manner.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.48&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor stimulated my thinking.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor evaluated my work fairly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor made good use of examples to clarify concepts.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor maintained a good learning environment.*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was accessible to students.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Express your judgment of the instructor&amp;rsquo;s overall teaching effectiveness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    58 respondents totaling 50.86% of registered students [* = 31 respondents]; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback-1&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Professor Howton always presented the material we covered in a very
interesting and engaging way. He made lecture an enjoyable
experience.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The lecture slides he provides are excellent.&lt;/strong&gt; The recitations are
helpful too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;It was great that he had the slides online ahead of time so that i
was able to take notes on the slides directly during the lecture.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot of things that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about philosophy before,
which was virtually nothing. &lt;strong&gt;This was the first step I took in
philosophy and I thought it was very engaging.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Robert&amp;rsquo;s major strengths mainly consisted in the way he could make
the difficult, abstract material as relatable and clear as possible to
the students in class. &lt;strong&gt;His lectures made the topics being covered
much more understandable and easier to relate to, and this greatly
helped my comprehension of the readings as well as on tests and
papers.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lectures were very organized and the information throughout the
semester was presented in an organized manner which was very helpful.
&lt;strong&gt;Robbie is very passionate about what he is teaching and was very
willing to answer questions and make sure we understood what he was
teaching during lecture.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2018spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2018spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-0210-introduction-to-modern-philosophy&#34;&gt;PHIL 0210 Introduction to Modern Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2018%20Spring%20-%20PHIL%200210%20-%20Combined%20Lecture%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor created an atmosphere that kept me engaged in course content.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.90&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.87&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was prepared for class.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor treated students with respect.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.52&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.74&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor was available to me (in-person, electronically, or both).*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor evaluated my work fairly.**&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor provided feedback that was helpful to me.***&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I learned a lot from this course.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.96&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    63 respondents totaling 56.76% of registered students [* = 36 respondents, ** = 45 respondents, *** = 42 respondents]; 5-point scale from 1 [hardly at all/ineffective] to 5 [to a very high degree/excellent].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The professor for this course is one of the best I have had at this university so far.&lt;/strong&gt; I like how he lays out the readings in a way thats [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] a lot easier to understand in the powerpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked how the lecture slides were available online before class, so that students could print them out and take notes on information presented by the instructor that were not on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progression of philosophical ideas was easy to follow, and seemed like a story that one could easily remember, rather than a jumbling of fragments of ideas from different people in different times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robbie is such a charismatic lecturer, so that really helped me get through the difficult content. Plus, I very much liked how he &amp;ldquo;prepped&amp;rdquo; us for the reading that week. Having the background knowledge really made the actual reading much smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert is a great public speaker and knew what he was talking about; he was able to answer any questions that people had over the course of the class. &lt;strong&gt;The powerpoints for the readings SAVED me––they&amp;rsquo;re incredibly helpful!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lectures and lecture slides were very helpful in understanding the readings. Having the slides available on course web [= Blackboard] was also fantastic.&lt;/strong&gt; Teacher was always willing to answer questions regardless of the large class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Howton always did a very good job of having examples or analogies that were easy to comprehend for very complex philosophical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked that we were provided the lecture slides to write notes on. Dr. Howton was so passionate and knowledgeable about the material and it really showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked that Prof. Howton was really into the material. &lt;strong&gt;You can tell that he is truly passionate about the ideas that he teaches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The professor was constantly stopping after a section and answer any and all questions pertaining to to [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;] the material in that section, and did so in a easy to understand way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Howton was very engaged with the material and always enthusiastic in lecture. Though the readings could sometimes be dry, hearing his presentation of the material made it much more understandable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2019spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2019spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phil-217-modern-philosophy&#34;&gt;PHIL 217: Modern Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/PHIL-217-01_Spring2019.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Instructor performance surpassed College and University benchmarks on &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; questions.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;**% Resp.**&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of instructor&amp;rsquo;s preparedness for classes was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.81&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s ability to communicate and explain effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s willingness to provide help when needed was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s use of class time effectively was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm (e.g. energy, encouragement, motivation) was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The level of instructor&amp;rsquo;s concern for students&amp;rsquo; learning and progress was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s attitude towards students was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The amount of knowledge gained from this course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The materials used in the course (books, handouts, readings, etc.) were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In terms of helping me learn the subject matter, the teaching methods were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The methods used to measure learning were:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The course&amp;rsquo;s organization was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor&amp;rsquo;s content knowledge was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.81&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the instructor was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.81&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the course was:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2.31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;64%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    7-point scale ranging from +3 [extremely good] to -3 [extremely poor]
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;select-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Select Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to thank you for your concern about for us in terms of learning the material and willingness to help when needed. The slides were very helpful as guidances&lt;/strong&gt; [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;]. I think we could spend more time on the paper topics in class as well, but you were again [text cuts off]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robbie is a great instructor. I did not feel that he needed to develop himself in any way. He is very talented and passionate and very knowledgeable. I am very glad I took this course despite the fact that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a phil. Major [&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;]!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course could have provided more time to discussion in discussion sessions rather than the reading reflections. &lt;strong&gt;The essay questions provided were really comprehensive and required good understanding of the content. Hence, they were really fun and&lt;/strong&gt; [text cuts off]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-instructor&#34;&gt;As Instructor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;koç-university&#34;&gt;Koç University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2019&#34;&gt;Fall 2019&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 453: Mind &amp;amp; Reality in the Ancient World: the Problem of the Criterion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HUMS 132: Illusion: When Appearances Deceive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2019&#34;&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 217: Modern Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2018&#34;&gt;Fall 2018&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 403: Topics in Ancient Philosophy: Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HUMS 132: Illusion: When Appearances Deceive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;university-of-pittsburgh&#34;&gt;University of Pittsburgh&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2018&#34;&gt;Spring 2018&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 0210: Introduction to Modern Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2017&#34;&gt;Fall 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 0080: Introduction to Philosophical Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2017&#34;&gt;Spring 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 1040: Aristotle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 0450: Theories of Knowledge and Reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2016&#34;&gt;Fall 2016&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 0460: Introduction to Philosophy of Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2016&#34;&gt;Spring 2016&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 1440: Philosophy of Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;university-of-toronto&#34;&gt;University of Toronto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;winter-2014&#34;&gt;Winter 2014&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 340: Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Singular Thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;as-tutorial-leader&#34;&gt;As Tutorial Leader&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;university-of-toronto-1&#34;&gt;University of Toronto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2013&#34;&gt;Fall 2013&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHL 205: Early Medieval Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2012--spring-2013&#34;&gt;Fall 2012&amp;ndash;Spring 2013&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHL 200: Ancient Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;summer-2011&#34;&gt;Summer 2011&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHL 210: 17th &amp;amp; 18th Century Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;texas-am-university&#34;&gt;Texas A&amp;amp;M University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;spring-2010&#34;&gt;Spring 2010&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 240: Symbolic Logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fall-2009&#34;&gt;Fall 2009&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHIL 240: Symbolic Logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For teachers and students alike, it is all too easy to regard the texts
that make up the standard philosophical curriculum as artifacts, relics
of views that were once compelling but have since&amp;mdash;perhaps &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt;
since&amp;mdash;been superseded. My guiding aim in teaching philosophy is to
dispel this tendency by creating the conditions for fruitful struggle
with these texts. One of the most valuable aspects of my philosophical
training was struggling to understand classic works of philosophy.
Confronted with a text I did not immediately understand, I was
challenged to ask questions and consider the underlying issues anew, and
in doing so I came to appreciate the text for reasons beyond its
historical or dialectical significance. The same, I&amp;rsquo;ve found, is true of
my students. Given the right tools, a student challenged by a text she
does not immediately understand will be encouraged to interrogate it,
rather than treat it as something that has already been understood and
rightly discarded; she will consider for herself the quality of the
reasons given for the view on offer; and she will seize the opportunity
to articulate, verbally and in writing, her own assessment of that view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job as a teacher of philosophy is to equip students with the
resources they need to struggle fruitfully with philosophical texts&amp;mdash;in
my lectures, in classroom activities, and in student assessment. I
design my courses around a model of guided reading. On this model,
students&amp;rsquo; first exposure to the content of an assigned text comes in
lecture, where they are presented with concise definitions of the
concepts and potted versions of the arguments they will encounter. I
distribute slides of my lectures, which I instruct the students to use
as an aid to spotting the relevant concepts and arguments as they read.
While students often report having difficulty with the reading, they are
just as often surprised at how much they&amp;rsquo;ve understood and how clearly
they can relate these concepts and arguments in class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I supplement this initial guided reading with a number of classroom
activities designed to reinforce and amplify students&amp;rsquo; comprehension. In
one activity, students take turns as &amp;ldquo;lead discussants&amp;rdquo; of pairs of
readings arguing on either side of a debate. The readings may be
historical, for instance the letters of Descartes and Elisabeth of
Bohemia on mind-body interaction; or they may be more contemporary, for
instance Smart and Kripke on the identity theory of mind. As lead
discussant, the student advocates for one of the opposed positions in
class discussion, answering questions and responding to challenges from
the other lead discussant, her peers, and me. Students prepare for this
role by writing an &amp;ldquo;executive summary&amp;rdquo; of their reading and by
rehearsing with me and the other lead discussant in office hours.
Students generally report a positive experience as a lead discussant,
and they seem to me remarkably fluent in their ability to explain and
defend often subtle philosophical positions. Another activity involves
tasking pairs of students with producing &amp;ldquo;fair copies&amp;rdquo; of class
meetings: polished transcripts of lectures and class discussion compiled
from the students&amp;rsquo; notes and corrected by me. The result is that
students construct their own lecture notes as guides for reading and
study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My policies for student assessment likewise emphasize fruitful struggle
with the assigned texts. An important evaluative tool in all of my
courses is argument analysis, in which I ask students to clarify,
reconstruct, and formulate objections to arguments in primary sources,
following a model I illustrate in my lectures. I stress the importance
of writing outlines and preliminary drafts, and I incentivize students
to do so by offering to discuss and comment on early outlines and
drafts. This policy is beneficial for two reasons. First, revising in
light of my comments enables the student to clarify her own
understanding of the relevant issues. Moreover, it gives me a basis for
evaluating the student&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;improvement&lt;/em&gt; in addition to the quality of the
resulting paper. In general I prefer anonymous assessment of exams, but
I try as much as possible to use a student&amp;rsquo;s improvement as a basis for
evaluating her performance in assignments demanding critical engagement
with philosophical texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistently positive student feedback on this model testifies to its
pedagogical efficacy. In evaluations of my courses, students regularly
report that the lecture slides, as well as other &amp;ldquo;preparatory&amp;rdquo;
material such as podcasts or YouTube videos, helped them understand the
assigned readings and the content of the lectures; that acting as lead
discussant enhanced their engagement with the material; and that class
assignments such as regular reading responses and composing &amp;ldquo;scribe
sheets&amp;rdquo; for the production of fair copies made a positive contribution
to their learning experience. I am also encouraged by consistently
positive feedback on my performance in the classroom: students often
remark on my enthusiasm as a lecturer, my willingness to answer
questions both inside and outside of the classroom, and my willingness
to discuss and comment on drafts of their assignments. In Spring 2019
the positive student feedback on my evaluations exceeded all College and
University benchmarks, for which reason I was recognized by my College
for teaching excellence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle claimed that teachers think they have achieved their goal when
they observe their students actually doing what they have been taught.
Rightly so. In my view the aim and chief pleasure of teaching philosophy
is to observe students doing what they could not do before: reading,
with increased understanding and appreciation, some of the great works
of our discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter 2014</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2014winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/dossier/2014winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;phl-340-issues-in-philosophy-of-mind-perception-and-singular-thought&#34;&gt;PHL 340: Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Singular Thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/files/evals/2014%20Winter%20-%20PHL%20340%20-%20Combined%20Report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Raw Data
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Quantitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.Dev.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I found the course intellectually stimulating.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The course provided me with a deeper understanding of the subject matter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor created a course atmosphere that was conducive to my learning.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Course projects, assignments, tests, and/or exams improved my understanding of the course material.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Course projects, assignments, tests and/or exams provided opportunity for me to demonstrate an understanding of the course material.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Overall, the quality of my learning experience in this course was….&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The instructor generated enthusiasm for learning in the course.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Compared to other courses, the workload for this course was…&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;0.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I would recommend this course to other students.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;3.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    16 respondents totaling 51.6% of registered students; 5-point scale from 1 [not at all/poor/very light] to 5 [a great deal/excellent/very heavy/strongly].
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;selected-qualitative-feedback&#34;&gt;Selected Qualitative Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Robert Howton, a PhD student in the department of Philosophy
instructed the entire course. This was the first course he has ever
taught. That being said, he did not exhibit any anxiety while
instructing the course. &lt;strong&gt;He was well-versed in each of the covered
topics, as was made evident in his explanation of the difficult
subject matter. He provided clear and concise lecture handouts, which
essentially covered all of the material in the class. Overall, I can
confidently say that Robert Howton was, by far, my favorite instructor
at the University of Toronto (PhD candidate, or otherwise).&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prof. Howton had to teach this course on his own because Prof.
Whiting was taking leave. In doing so however he was excellent. &lt;strong&gt;He
provided us with extremely helpful outlines of his lectures, allowing
me to keep attention on him while also adding things down on the
handout.&lt;/strong&gt; While he did sometimes go a bit fast, the minute anyone
asked him to repeat a concept he would do so and make it ever the more
clear. &lt;strong&gt;Though he&amp;rsquo;s a graduate student, I thoroughly enjoyed learning
with him as my professor. He definitely demonstrated how interested
and enthusiastic he was about the course material, and I would
definitely take another course with him in the future.&lt;/strong&gt; Great job.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great, explained clearly the topics. Everything was done slowly so
everyone understands. There was a use of many examples. Small class so
all questions were answered. Instructor helped out with any problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Robert Howton is a fantastic instructor. The subject matter was very
interesting and very intellectually stimulating.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Robbie always provided a lot of support and tried to go slowly when
concepts were unclear.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
