<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work | Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Work</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Robert Howton</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.roberthowton.com/images/icon_hu54747066b42249938da40e4cc06b81d2_111739_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Work</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Instructions</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All students of PHIL 453/553-01 are required to make at least one presentation over the course of the semester. (Graduate students will make two.) Presentations will be given on Thursdays, and will be aimed at facilitating class discussion of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/spring2021/schedule/#schedule-of-topics--readings&#34;&gt;one of the pieces of secondary literature assigned for that week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students can sign up for presentations via Blackboard. The deadline for choosing a presentation date and topic is &lt;strong&gt;2 March&lt;/strong&gt; by 23:59. Students who have not signed up by that time will have a date and topic chosen by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;presentation-format-and-questions&#34;&gt;Presentation Format and Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each presentation must be accompanied by a slide show, which will be submitted to me on the day of the presentation. Slide shows should dedicate a slide (or a section of the slide show) to answering each of the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, presenters will be asked to share discussion questions&amp;mdash;which may or may not be identical to the student&amp;rsquo;s answer to question 5 below&amp;mdash;no later than the Tuesday before the Thursday they are scheduled to present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the problem or puzzle the paper addresses?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the papers we will be discussing are &lt;em&gt;interpretive&lt;/em&gt;, aimed at developing and defending a reading of a passage (or set of passages) of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s corpus, the problem/puzzle in question will most likely concern an &lt;em&gt;interpretive&lt;/em&gt; difficulty, a challenge for understanding some aspect of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How have scholars previously proposed to address or solve the problem with which the paper is concerned?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, what other interpretations does the author intend to criticize?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What alternative does the author propose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the author, in contrast to previous scholars, propose to address or solve the problem in question?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does the author think their alternative is superior to previous attempts to solve or address the problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What evidence and/or arguments does the author put forward in favor of their interpretation, and why, according to the author, do these considerations rule out competing proposals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What questions might be raised about the author&amp;rsquo;s proposal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the considerations the author puts forward in favor of their interpretation &lt;em&gt;in fact&lt;/em&gt; provide conclusive support for that interpretation? What other substantive questions arise if the author&amp;rsquo;s interpretation is correct? What response(s) might be given on behalf of the interpretations the author criticizes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;assessment&#34;&gt;Assessment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentations are worth a maximum of 20 points and will be assessed on the quality of their answers to the above questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points Earned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superlative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&amp;ndash;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to all questions are clear, concise, and insightful.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excellent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&amp;ndash;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to all questions are clear and concise, but perhaps not insightful.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfactory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&amp;ndash;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to most questions are clear and perhaps insightful.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Needs Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&amp;ndash;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to most questions are clear, but none are especially insightful.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Needs Serious Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&amp;ndash;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to most questions are unclear.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unsatisfactory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&amp;ndash;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Answers to all questions are either unclear or incomplete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Commentary</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/commentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/assignments/commentary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-commentary&#34;&gt;What is a Commentary?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;commentary&lt;/strong&gt; is a detailed, line-by-line &amp;ldquo;explication&amp;rdquo; of a text. From Late Antiquity through the Middle Ages, several commentaries were commentaries were written on a wide variety of ancient texts, each with the aims of (1) explaining difficult aspects of the text for novice readers, (2) resolving textual ambiguities, and (3) exploring the philosophical, literary, or historical questions raised by the text. For similar reasons modern &amp;ldquo;critical editions&amp;rdquo; of ancient texts are also often accompanied by commentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-structure-of-a-commentary&#34;&gt;The Structure of a Commentary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentaries can differ significantly in organization and focus depending on the commentator&amp;rsquo;s interest, whether it is the literary character of a text, its historical transmission, its connection with other ancient literature, or its philosophical content. But whatever its focus, any commentary will have something like the following structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The commentary will begin by introducing the text, giving its overall context, aims, and reception by ancient and modern readers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The commentator then proceeds slowly through the text, section-by-section, line-by-line, (a) clarifying the meaning of and (b) raising questions about the text, (c) making cross-references to other relevant passages, and (d) discussing alternative interpretations of the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each new section to be discussed is introduced by a &lt;strong&gt;lemma&lt;/strong&gt;, an abbreviated quotation of a line of the text that introduces the issues to be discussed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paraphrase is discouraged; claims referenced from the text are cited by page and line number (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, Stephanus pages for Plato&amp;rsquo;s works, Bekker lines for Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;requirements-for-your-philosophical-commentary&#34;&gt;Requirements for Your Philosophical Commentary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be writing a &lt;em&gt;philosophical&lt;/em&gt; commentary. This means that your commentary will be dedicated to explicating the philosophical content of the text you choose. Here are some features your philosophical commentary must include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avoid paraphrase.&lt;/em&gt; It will be more helpful to your reader if you &lt;em&gt;explain&lt;/em&gt; the meaning of a passage, rather than put the same claim into different words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Break down&lt;/em&gt; the text into its logical components; dedicate a section of your commentary to each component of the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consider alternative readings.&lt;/em&gt; Many sentences will be ambiguous. Pointing out the ambiguities and discussing the implications of alternative readings will help you and your reader understand the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference other passages&lt;/em&gt;, especially those which illuminate the context of the passage or contain more in depth discussion of ideas referenced in the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep the context in focus.&lt;/em&gt; What is the author&amp;rsquo;s project in the local context of the passage? What is the project of the containing work as a whole? How ought the context influence our interpretation of the text on which you are commenting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
