<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Robert Howton</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Robert Howton</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle&#39;s Arguments for the Perceptual Criterion</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/post/krisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 11:52:27 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/post/krisis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In several passages of his natural scientific treatises, Aristotle expresses commitment to the thesis that sense-perception (&lt;em&gt;aisthêsis&lt;/em&gt;) is &lt;em&gt;kritikê&lt;/em&gt;, discriminative or (better, as I shall argue) &lt;em&gt;criterial&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:CITE-passages&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:CITE-passages&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Though it is nowhere presented as such, this is in fact one of the most controversial claims of his psychology: Aristotle is alone among his contemporaries and predecessors in affirming the thesis, whereas it was explicitly &lt;em&gt;denied&lt;/em&gt; by almost all others who considered it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/post/krisis/texts/#text-1-anaxagoras-59b21-dk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text 1&lt;/a&gt;, Text 2, Text 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commentators have come increasingly to appreciate the significance of this thesis for Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s psychology. So far, however, no commentators have addressed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;against-recent-interpretations-of-perceptual-discrimination&#34;&gt;Against recent interpretations of perceptual discrimination:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answering these questions leads us to reject two claims central to many recent interpretations of perceptual discrimination in Aristotle:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Aristotle regards being κριτική as &lt;em&gt;essential&lt;/em&gt; to, or partially &lt;em&gt;definitive&lt;/em&gt; of, αἴσθησις: see most recently Perälä, but also by Ebert, De Haas [CHECK Corcilius, Herzberg, Johansen]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Aristotle, in stressing that αἴσθησις is κριτική, is emphasizing that the power to perceive is, in some primary sense, a power to discriminate or tell apart sensible qualities and sensible bodies. (A line of interpretation initially proposed by Ebert but which has been accepted by all [?] subsequent interpreters.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-contrast-i-ll-argue-that&#34;&gt;In contrast, I&amp;rsquo;ll argue that:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power to discriminate is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a feature of the &lt;em&gt;essence&lt;/em&gt; of the senses, but rather a &lt;em&gt;demonstrable&lt;/em&gt; feature of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aristotle provides two arguments aimed at demonstrating that αἴσθησις is κριτική, one final causal and one formal causal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;final causal argument&lt;/em&gt;, αἴσθησις is and must be κριτική in order to promote the ends for whose sake it belongs to living things that have αἴσθησις:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;αἴσθησις is present in all animals for the sake of survival and, ultimately, reproduction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the presence of αἴσθησις additionally promotes animals&amp;rsquo; cognitive function;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, in humans, αἴσθησις is cited as the capacity from which potential knowers acquire knowledge of the indemonstrable principles of a demonstrative science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;formal causal&lt;/em&gt; argument, αἴσθησις is κριτική because each sense (αἴσθησις) is a mean state of the opposition present in the qualities each perceives, and the mean is in every case κριτική.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seen in the light of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s arguments, the conclusion that αἴσθησις is κριτική appears radically different: not an affirmation that perception is the cognition of difference but of the basic fidelity of the senses. For Aristotle, the senses are not only a source of knowledge; perception itself is a form of knowledge. And the basis for this claim is that perception, in its most basic form, is criterial for the presence of the sensible qualities it perceives; that perceivers, by virtue of having the capacity to perceive, occupy a privileged perspective with respect to the sensible objects and qualities of which they are critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aristotle-s-predecessors-on-perceptual-κρίσις&#34;&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s predecessors on perceptual κρίσις&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anaxagoras&#34;&gt;Anaxagoras&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;democritus&#34;&gt;Democritus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;plato&#34;&gt;Plato&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aristotle-in-response-to-his-predecessors&#34;&gt;Aristotle in response to his predecessors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-arguments-for-perceptual-κρίσις&#34;&gt;Two arguments for perceptual κρίσις&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-final-causal-argument&#34;&gt;The final causal argument&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-formal-causal-argument&#34;&gt;The formal causal argument&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aristotle-s-protagoreanism&#34;&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Protagoreanism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;concluding-remarks&#34;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foregoing has sketched a fragment of a debate whose origin and terminus far exceed the scope of this paper. At its inception is a pre-Platonic skepticism about the reliability of the senses, at its terminus a sophisticated between skeptics and so-called dogmatists about the status of perception as a &amp;ldquo;criterion of truth&amp;rdquo; and source of knowledge. My hope is that this paper has shown that Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s case for the fidelity of the senses is more formative for this debate than we have previously acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:CITE-passages&#34;&gt;CITE passages &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:CITE-passages&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
