<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lectures | Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lectures</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Robert Howton</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.roberthowton.com/images/icon_hu54747066b42249938da40e4cc06b81d2_111739_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hylomorphism-defined&#34;&gt;Hylomorphism defined&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Hylomorphism&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The metaphysical theory that a &lt;strong&gt;substance&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;composite&lt;/em&gt; of &amp;ldquo;form&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;morphē&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;eidos&lt;/em&gt;) and &amp;ldquo;matter&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;hulē&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;


















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/substance.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/substance.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;parsing-the-definition&#34;&gt;Parsing the definition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hylomorphism posits a relationship between three items: &lt;strong&gt;substance&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;form&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;matter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;substance--ousia&#34;&gt;Substance (&lt;em&gt;ousia&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comes from the from the Greek &amp;ldquo;to be&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;einai&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Aristotle, has a variety of meanings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Property&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;that which is one&amp;rsquo;s own&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Being&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;existence&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt;) - Charles Kahn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both senses seem to be at work in Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s conception of substance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1--substance-as-essence&#34;&gt;(1) Substance as essence&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Aristotle, the &lt;em&gt;ousia&lt;/em&gt; of a thing is identical to &amp;ldquo;what it is&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;ti esti&lt;/em&gt;) or, as it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes known, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;essence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;what it is&amp;rdquo; corresponds to a thing&amp;rsquo;s definition (&lt;em&gt;horos&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;horismos&lt;/em&gt;, lit. &amp;ldquo;limits&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;boundaries&amp;rdquo;), or what we know when we know what something is, it&amp;rsquo;s essence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association between &lt;em&gt;ousia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ti esti&lt;/em&gt;, and definition precedes Aristotle. Recall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socrates&lt;/strong&gt; (in the Platonic dialogues at least) famously traces disputes about the status of some action as virtuous, or the properties of a given virtue, to questions about &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; that virtue &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plato, &lt;em&gt;Meno&lt;/em&gt; 70a&amp;ndash;b&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MENO: Can you tell me, Socrates, can virtue be taught? Or is it not
teachable but the result of practice, or is it neither of these, but men possess
it by nature or in some other way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOCRATES: &amp;hellip;I myself, Meno, am as poor as my fellow citizens in this matter, and I
blame myself for my complete ignorance about virtue. If I do not know
what something is, how could I know what qualities it possesses? Or do
you think that someone who does not know at all who Meno is could
know whether he is good-looking or rich or well-born, or the opposite of
these? Do you think that is possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plato&lt;/strong&gt; famously follows Socrates in thinking of the objects of knowledge as corresponding to the &amp;ldquo;what it is&amp;rdquo;, or essence, of what we know&amp;mdash;with one major difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plato, &lt;em&gt;Phaedo&lt;/em&gt; 70b&amp;ndash;c&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then before we began to see or hear or otherwise perceive, we must
have possessed knowledge of the Equal itself if we were about to refer
our sense perceptions of equal objects to it, and realized that all of them
were eager to be like it, but were inferior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That follows from what has been said, Socrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we began to see and hear and otherwise perceive right after birth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must then have acquired the knowledge of the Equal before this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems then that we must have possessed it before birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if we had this knowledge, we knew before birth and immedi-
ately after not only the Equal, but the Greater and the Smaller and all such
things, for our present argument is no more about the Equal than about
d the Beautiful itself, the Good itself, the Just, the Pious and, as I say, about
all those things which we mark with the seal of &amp;ldquo;what it is,&amp;rdquo; both when
we are putting questions and answering them. So we must have acquired
knowledge of them all before we were born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how Aristotle characterizes the difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aristotle, &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; A 6, 987a28&amp;ndash;b12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the systems we have named came the philosophy of
Plato, which in most respects followed these thinkers, but had
peculiarities that distinguished it [30] from the philosophy of
the Italians. For, having in his youth first become familiar
with Cratylus and with the Heraclitean doctrines (that all
sensible things are ever in a state of flux and there is no
knowledge about them), these views he held even in later
years. Socrates, however, was busying himself about ethical
matters and [987b1] neglecting the world of nature as a whole
but seeking the universal in these ethical matters, and fixed
thought for the first time on definitions; Plato accepted his
teaching, but held that the problem applied not to any sensible
thing but to entities [5] of another kind—for this reason, that
the common definition could not be a definition of any
sensible thing, as they were always changing. Things of this
other sort, then, he called Ideas, and sensible things, he said,
were apart from these, and were all called after these; for the
multitude of things which have the same name as the Form
exist by participation in it. Only the name ‘participation’ was
new; for the [10] Pythagoreans say that things exist by
imitation of numbers, and Plato says they exist by
participation, changing the name. But what the participation
or the imitation of the Forms could be they left an open
question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2--substance-as-what-is&#34;&gt;(2) Substance as &amp;ldquo;what is&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt; in Presocratic thought&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s testimony alludes to a distinction that occupied Plato as well as Presocrates like Parmenides, Melissus, Empedocles, Anaxagoras, and Democritus: the distinction between &amp;ldquo;what is&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt;) and &amp;ldquo;what is not&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;to mē on&lt;/em&gt;).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmenides and his Eleatic &amp;ldquo;school&amp;rdquo; famously challenged the possibility of change (or &amp;ldquo;coming to be&amp;rdquo;) on the grounds that it is impossible for there to be anything except &lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick &amp;amp; dirty version of the Eleatic argument:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmenides: not only is it impossible for &lt;em&gt;to mē on&lt;/em&gt; to be, it is impossible to think or even say &lt;em&gt;to mē on&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If what-is &amp;ldquo;came to be&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;ginesthai&lt;/em&gt;), it previously was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is not cannot be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, what-is did not come to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, coming to be (change) is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ontological theories of the so-called Eleatic pluralists&amp;mdash;Empedocles, Anaxagoras, Democritus&amp;mdash;are often read as attempts to explain change in a way consistent with Eleatic principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empedocles&lt;/strong&gt; argued that what-is (the four elements) exists in an eternal cycle of combination and separation governed by the causal principles Love and Strife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anaxagoras&lt;/strong&gt; argued that &amp;ldquo;all is in all&amp;rdquo;, and that the macroscopic differences in things are brought about by alternating shifts in the preponderance of some properties over others in different portions of the cosmic mixture, the changes being brought about and ordered by &lt;em&gt;Nous&lt;/em&gt; (mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Democritus&lt;/strong&gt; (and Leucippus) argued that &lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;to mē on&lt;/em&gt; both equally are: &lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt; are indivisible (atomic) bodies, &lt;em&gt;to mē on&lt;/em&gt; is the void through which they travel, combine, and separate with one another. Macroscopic change is just the combination and separation of unchanging microscopic atoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;to on&lt;/em&gt; in Plato&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plato picks up on this distinction, dividing the objects of cognition between coming-to-be (&lt;em&gt;genesis&lt;/em&gt;), which we apprehend by means of the senses, and what is (&lt;em&gt;ousia&lt;/em&gt;), which we apprehend by thought. (&lt;em&gt;Republic&lt;/em&gt; 7, 534a)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More strikingly, Plato seems to have &lt;em&gt;ontologically&lt;/em&gt; separated the objects of perception and the objects of thought, and reserved the designation &amp;ldquo;real being&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;to ontōs on&lt;/em&gt;) for the objects of thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plato, &lt;em&gt;Timaeus&lt;/em&gt; 52a&amp;ndash;b&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these things are so, we must agree that that which keeps its own
form unchangingly, which has not been brought into being and is not
destroyed, which neither receives into itself anything else from anywhere
else, nor itself enters into anything else anywhere, is one thing. It is invisi-
ble&amp;mdash;it cannot be perceived by the senses at all&amp;mdash;and it is the role of
understanding to study it. The second thing is that which shares the other&amp;rsquo;s
name and resembles it. This thing can be perceived by the senses, and it
has been begotten. It is constantly borne along, now coming to be in a
certain place and then perishing out of it. It is apprehended by opinion,
which involves sense perception. And the third type is space, which exists
always and cannot be destroyed. It provides afixed state for all things
that come to be. It is itself apprehended by a kind of bastard reasoning
that does not involve sense perception, and it is hardly even an object of
conviction. We look at it as in a dream when we say that everything that
exists must of necessity be somewhere, in some place and occupying some
space, and that that which doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist somewhere, whether on earth or
in heaven, doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distinction is a central component of Plato&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Theory of Forms&amp;rdquo;, so called because he reserved the word &lt;em&gt;eidos&lt;/em&gt;, form, for the real beings apprehended solely by thought&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aristotle-on-substance&#34;&gt;Aristotle on substance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What is a &lt;em&gt;substance&lt;/em&gt; in Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s theory?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Answer&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Depends on where you look!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories:&lt;/strong&gt; Substance is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the strictest sense, what is &amp;ldquo;neither said of nor present in a subject&amp;rdquo; (2a11&amp;ndash;13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A certain this&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;tode ti&lt;/em&gt;), i.e., something &amp;ldquo;indivisible&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;numerically one&amp;rdquo; (3b10&amp;ndash;11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metaphysics Z:&lt;/strong&gt; The substance &lt;em&gt;of a thing&lt;/em&gt; (e.g. some &lt;em&gt;tode ti&lt;/em&gt;) could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;universal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The genus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  subject of predication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;cause of being&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;Z&lt;/em&gt; 17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observation:&lt;/strong&gt; Matter and form play a significant role of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s discussion of substance in &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; Z, but &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Puzzle:&lt;/strong&gt; How do the &lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; Z accounts of substance relate? Do Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s views on substance develop? If so, how does the introduction of hylomorphism influence the development of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s views?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;form--morphē-eidos&#34;&gt;Form (&lt;em&gt;morphē&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;eidos&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle has two words for form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eidos&lt;/em&gt; (lit., &amp;ldquo;look&amp;rdquo;), which comes from the (related) Greek words &amp;ldquo;to see&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;oida&lt;/em&gt;) and &amp;ldquo;to know&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;eidenai&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morphē&lt;/em&gt;,  which means &amp;ldquo;shape&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;appearance&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is distinctive about Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s conception of form?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards an answer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what Aristotle says of Plato&amp;rsquo;s reception of Socrates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socrates was the first to draw attention to definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plato, however, was convinced that the sensible world was in a state of constant flux and change, which meant that what definitions &lt;em&gt;define&lt;/em&gt; could not be anything sensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence the objects of definition must be &lt;em&gt;separate&lt;/em&gt; from the mutable objects of perception and, unlike them, imperceptible, stable, unchanging, fully what they are, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle famously &lt;em&gt;denies&lt;/em&gt; that that forms are separable in the way Plato claimed (see &lt;em&gt;On Ideas&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that forms are separable from sensible &amp;ldquo;particulars&amp;rdquo; implies that forms could be &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; sensibles (&lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; Δ 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the contrary, Aristotle believes that &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; would be without &amp;ldquo;primary&amp;rdquo; substances:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aristotle, &lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt; 5, 2a35&amp;ndash;b5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the other things are either said of the primary substances
as subjects or in [35] them as subjects. This is clear from an
examination of cases. For example, animal is predicated of
man and therefore also of the individual man; for were it
predicated of none of the individual men it would not be
predicated of man at all. Again, colour is [2b1] in body and
therefore also in an individual body; for were it not in some
individual body it would not be in body at all. Thus all the
other things are either said of the primary substances as
subjects or in them as subjects. So if the primary substances
[5] did not exist it would be impossible for any of the other
things to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aside--little-p--platonic-vs-dot--little-a--aristotelian-theories-of-universals&#34;&gt;Aside:  (little &amp;ldquo;p&amp;rdquo;) platonic vs. (little &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo;) aristotelian theories of universals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Universal&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;said of&amp;rdquo; many things, e.g. redness, &amp;ldquo;human being&amp;rdquo;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Particular&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;said of&amp;rdquo; many things, e.g. scarlet, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; scarlet letter, Socrates&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Would &lt;em&gt;scarlet&lt;/em&gt; exist if nothing were scarlet colored?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Little &amp;ldquo;p&amp;rdquo;) platonic response:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes! Universals are not ontologically dependent on their particular instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Little &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo;) aristotelian response:&lt;/strong&gt; No! Universals depend on their particular instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;controversies-over-aristotle-s-theory-of-form&#34;&gt;Controversies over Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s theory of form&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are Aristotelian forms &lt;em&gt;particular&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;universal&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If form corresponds to the &lt;em&gt;essence&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;definition&lt;/em&gt; of a thing, is it also the &lt;em&gt;substance&lt;/em&gt; of that thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is form always the form of some &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;matter--hulē&#34;&gt;Matter (&lt;em&gt;hulē&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literally means &amp;ldquo;wood&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;stick&amp;rdquo;, but Aristotle associates it with two features of particulars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;subject&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;substratum&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;hupokeimenon&lt;/em&gt;) of which properties are predicated. (Aristotle associates substance with this too.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That from which&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;to ex hou&lt;/em&gt;): most intuitively, the materials from which an object (Socrates or a chair) is fashioned or comes to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle associates matter (or the &amp;ldquo;material cause&amp;rdquo;) with the theories of the earlier Ionian &amp;ldquo;natural philosophers&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;phusiologoi&lt;/em&gt;): Thales (everything is [from] water), Anaximander (everything is from the &amp;ldquo;unlimited&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em&gt;apeiron&lt;/em&gt;), Anaximenes (everything is [from] air):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aristotle, &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; A 3, 983b5&amp;ndash;19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the first philosophers, most thought the principles which
were of the nature of matter were the only principles of all things;
that of which all things that are consist, and from which they first
come to be, and into which they are finally [10] resolved (the
substance remaining, but changing in its modifications), this
they say is the element and the principle of things, and
therefore they think nothing is either generated or destroyed,
since this sort of entity is always conserved, as we say
Socrates neither comes to be absolutely when he comes to be
beautiful or musical, [15] nor ceases to be when he loses these
characteristics, because the substratum, Socrates himself,
remains. So they say nothing else comes to be or ceases to be;
for there must be some entity—either one or more than
one—from which all other things come to be, it being
conserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No clear Socratic or Platonic precedent&amp;mdash;although compare Plato&amp;rsquo;s notion of &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;chōrē&lt;/em&gt;) in &lt;em&gt;Timaeus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle often speaks of matter as a relative term: all matter is the matter &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; something:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The matter of the chair is wood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The matter of the wood is earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the matter of the chair is not earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;matter is the &lt;strong&gt;potential&lt;/strong&gt; for form, which, in turn, is that &lt;strong&gt;actualization&lt;/strong&gt; of some material potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions-for-unit-1&#34;&gt;Questions for Unit 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Aristotle understand &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;substance&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Organon&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a framework within which we can make senses of a &lt;em&gt;hylomorphic&lt;/em&gt; analysis of substance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit 1 | Background: Ontology &amp; Explanation in the Organon</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 15:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Organon&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;lit. &amp;ldquo;tool, instrument&amp;rdquo;; a collective name for Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s logico-epistemological treatises:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt;, on predicates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;De Interpretatione&lt;/em&gt;, on things said in combination&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prior&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt;, on demonstrative scientific knowledge (&lt;em&gt;epistēmē apodeiktikē&lt;/em&gt;), including Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s categorical logic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topics&lt;/em&gt;, on dialectic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sophistical Refutations&lt;/em&gt;, on fallacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-ontology-and-explanation-in-the-organon&#34;&gt;Background: Ontology &amp;amp; Explanation in the &lt;em&gt;Organon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;categories-1-5&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt; 1&amp;ndash;5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cat-dot-1-three-semantico-ontological-distinctions&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 1: Three semantico-ontological distinctions:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;homonymous&lt;/strong&gt; iff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; have a name (&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;) in common, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the &amp;ldquo;definition of being&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;logos tēs ousias&lt;/em&gt;) of &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;different&lt;/span&gt; in &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;synonymous&lt;/strong&gt; iff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; have a name (&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;) in common,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the &amp;ldquo;definition of being&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;logos tēs ousias&lt;/em&gt;) of &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;the same&lt;/span&gt; in &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;paronymous&lt;/strong&gt; iff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; get their name from the same &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;, but&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt; differ in grammatical category (&lt;em&gt;ptōsis&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cat-dot-2-a-fourfold-division-of-beings--ta-onta&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 2: A fourfold division of beings (&lt;em&gt;ta onta&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Said-of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¬Said-of&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Present-in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-Substantial Universals (Knowledge)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-Substantial Particulars (Literacy)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;¬Present-in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Secondary Substances (Human Being)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Primary Substances (Socrates)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some definitions (&lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 5, 2a19&amp;ndash;35)&amp;hellip;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;predicated&lt;/strong&gt; of some subject &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; if (and only if?):
∀M(&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; is said of &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; → &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; is said of &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;said of&lt;/strong&gt; some subject &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; if (and only if?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is (truly) predicated of &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N&amp;rsquo;s definition is also (truly) predicated of &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;present in&lt;/strong&gt; a subject  &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; iff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt; is &amp;ldquo;in&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;, not as a part, and cannot be separately from what it is in. (1a24&amp;ndash;5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; nor its definition is (non-paronymously) predicated of &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;.
(Socrates is &lt;em&gt;brave&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;bravery&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mapping-said-of-and-present-in-relations&#34;&gt;Mapping said-of and present-in relations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Said-of relations and genus-species trees&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/genus-species.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/genus-species.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present-in relations and &amp;ldquo;kooky objects&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kooky object
: an &amp;ldquo;accidental&amp;rdquo; compound of a (primary) substance and an attribute present in that substance, e.g. &lt;em&gt;the pale man&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;musical Socrates&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; 

















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/kookyobject.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/kookyobject.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;substance-in-cat-dot-5&#34;&gt;Substance in &lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 5, 2a11&amp;ndash;19 (Ackrill tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A substance—that which is called a substance most
strictly, primarily, and most of all—is that which is neither
said of a subject nor in a subject, e.g. the [15] individual man
or the individual horse. The species in which the things
primarily called substances are, are called secondary
substances, as also are the genera of these species. For
example, the individual man belongs in a species, man, and
animal is a genus of the species; so these—both man and
animal—are called secondary substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;characteristics-of-substance-in-cat-dot-5&#34;&gt;Characteristics of substance in &lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 5&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substance is not present in anything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary substances&lt;/strong&gt; are neither said of nor present in anything else as subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondary substances&lt;/strong&gt; are said of primary substances, but present in nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentia&lt;/strong&gt; too are not present in anything as subject, but they are neither primary nor secondary substances&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; How then do differentia fit into the &lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 2 division of beings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything called from them are so-called synonymously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No contrary of substance&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;G&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;contraries&lt;/strong&gt; iff ∀x(Fx→¬Gx) ∀x(Gx→¬Fx)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;G&lt;/em&gt; are &lt;strong&gt;contradictories&lt;/strong&gt; iff ∀x[(¬Fx→Gx) &amp;amp; (¬Gx→Fx)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substances do not admit of a more and less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most distinctive&amp;rdquo;: substances are (1) numerically one but (2) capable of receiving contraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cat. 5, 4a10&amp;ndash;21 (Ackrill tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems most distinctive of substance that what is
numerically one and the [10] same is able to receive
contraries. In no other case could one bring forward anything,
numerically one, which is able to receive contraries. For
example, a colour which is numerically one and the same will
not be black and white, nor will numerically one and the same
action be bad and good; and similarly with everything [15]
else that is not substance. A substance, however, numerically
one and the same, is able to receive contraries. For example,
an individual man—one and the same—becomes pale at one
time and dark at another, and hot and cold, and bad and [20]
good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ontology-and-explanation-in-the-prior-analytics&#34;&gt;Ontology &amp;amp; Explanation in the &lt;em&gt;Prior Analytics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;basics-of-aristotelian-syllogistic&#34;&gt;Basics of Aristotelian Syllogistic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;term&lt;/strong&gt; (A, B, C, &amp;hellip;) is what is predicated and what it is predicated of in a &lt;strong&gt;premise&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;premise&lt;/strong&gt; is a sentence that affirms or denies one &lt;strong&gt;term&lt;/strong&gt; of another:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affirmation:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;A belongs to B&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Denial:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;A does not belong to B&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premises are distinguished by &lt;strong&gt;quantity&lt;/strong&gt; (and &lt;strong&gt;quality&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. necessity, possibility).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affirmation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Denial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A belongs to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A belongs to &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A belongs to &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; belong to some B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schematically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Affirmative:&lt;/strong&gt; AaB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Negative:&lt;/strong&gt; AeB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Affirmative:&lt;/strong&gt; AiB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Particular Negative:&lt;/strong&gt; AoB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;syllogism&lt;/strong&gt; is &amp;ldquo;a &lt;em&gt;logos&lt;/em&gt; in which, certain things being posited (i.e., the premises), something else (i.e., the conclusion) results by necessity because these things are so&amp;rdquo; (24b18&amp;ndash;20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s syllogistic is the formal study of what combinations of premises produce syllogisms, using three tools:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three &lt;strong&gt;rules of conversion&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;APr.&lt;/em&gt; 1.2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AeB → BeA:&lt;/strong&gt; If A belongs to no B, B belongs to no A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AiB → BiA:&lt;/strong&gt; If A belongs to some B, B belongs to some A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AaB → BiA:&lt;/strong&gt; If A belongs to all B, B belongs to some A.
(Note: Aristotle assumes terms are non-empty!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguments from impossibility (&lt;em&gt;reductio ad absurdum&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I call a syllogism perfect if it requires nothing beyond the things posited for the necessity to be evident.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Aristotle, syllogisms of the First Figure are all perfect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mnemonic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Form&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Barbara&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaB, BaC \vdash AaC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Celarent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeB, BaC \vdash AeC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Darii&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaB, BiC \vdash AiC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ferio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeB, BiC \vdash AoC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syllogisms in the second and third figures proved by conversion and reduction to one of the &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; first figure syllogisms; figures differ according to where the &lt;strong&gt;middle term&lt;/strong&gt; (the term that appears in both premises) appears in each premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second Figure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mnemonic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Form&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ceasare&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeB, AaC \vdash BeC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Camestres&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaB, AeC \vdash BeC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Festino&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeB, AiC \vdash BoC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Baroco&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaB, AoC \vdash BoC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third Figure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mnemonic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Form&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Darapti&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaC, BaC \vdash AiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Felapton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeC, BaC \vdash AoB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disamis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AiC, BaC \vdash AiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Datisi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AaC, BiC \vdash AiB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bocardo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AoC, BaC \vdash AoB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ferison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AeC, BiC \vdash AoB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;syllogistic-and-explanation&#34;&gt;Syllogistic and Explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Demonstration&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A &amp;ldquo;knowledge-yielding&amp;rdquo; syllogism; a syllogism grasp of which imparts scientific knowledge (&lt;em&gt;epistēmē&lt;/em&gt;) of the conclusion.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posterior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 1.2, 71b9-12 (Barnes tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think we understand (= know scientifically) a thing &lt;em&gt;simpliciter&lt;/em&gt;
(and not in the sophistic fashion accidentally) whenever we think
we are aware both that the explanation [10] because of which the
object is is its explanation, and that it is not possible for this
to be otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The syllogistic is a necessary preliminary to the study of demonstration and demonstrative scientific knowledge &amp;ldquo;because syllogism is more universal than demonstration, for a demonstration is a kind of syllogism, but not every syllogism is a demonstration&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;APr.&lt;/em&gt; 1.4, 28&amp;ndash;31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the universal patterns of which demonstrations are special instances, Aristotle thinks the syllogistic implies a method for inquiry and explanation in all disciplines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 1.30, 46a3&amp;ndash;10 (Striker tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the method is the same for all subjects, in philosophy as well as
in the technical or mathematical disciplines. For one must discern for
both terms what belongs to them and what they belong to, and be
supplied with as many of those terms as possible. One must examine
them with respect to the three terms, in one way when refuting, in
another way when establishing something; and when it is a question
of truth, from the terms that are listed as belonging truly, for dialecti-
cal syllogisms from premisses according to opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method presupposes the classification of beings similar to the one articulated in the &lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 1.27, 43a25&amp;ndash;43&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now of all the things there are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some are such that they cannot be predicated truly and universally of anything else (for instance, Cleon or Callias, that is, what is individual and perceptible), but other things may be predicated of them (for each of these is both a man and an animal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things are themselves predicated of others , but nothing else is prior and predicated of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some things are both predicated themselves of others and others of them, as man is predicated of Callias and animal of man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That [1] some things are by nature such as to be said of nothing else is clear, for just about every perceptible thing is such as not to be predicated of anything except accidentally&amp;mdash;for we do sometimes say that the white thing there is Socrates, or that what is approaching is Callias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But [2] that one also comes to a halt if one goes upwards,  we will explain later; for the moment let this be assumed. (&lt;em&gt;APo.&lt;/em&gt; 1.3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with respect to those things one cannot demonstrate that something else is predicated of them (except perhaps as a matter of mere opinion), but only that they themselves are predicated of other things;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nor can one demonstrate that individuals are said of other things, but only that other things are said of them. But clearly the intermediate things admit of both, for they themselves will be said of others and others of them. And by and large arguments and investigations are mostly concerned with these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What of [3], the terms that are both predicated and predicated of? Aristotle continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prior Analytics&lt;/em&gt; 1.28 43b1&amp;ndash;11 (Striker tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So one must select the premisses about each thing in the following
way: &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt;, set down the thing itself, its definitions, and whatever
properties are peculiar to it; &lt;strong&gt;after that&lt;/strong&gt;, whatever follows this thing,
what is followed by it, and whatever cannot belong to the thing. (One
need not select the terms to which the thing itself cannot belong, since
the privative premiss converts.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the terms that follow one must also distinguish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;those that are predicated in the definition,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;those that are peculiar properties,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and those that are predicated as accidents; and among those, which sort is predicated only as a matter of opinion and which according to the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the more such terms one has available, the faster one will hit upon a conclusion, and the more these belong in truth, the more one will hit upon a demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Which of 1&amp;ndash;3 are said-of predications, and which are present-in predications?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--listend--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a ready supply of terms, Aristotle argues (&lt;em&gt;APr.&lt;/em&gt; 1.28) we can construct each kind of proposition (&lt;em&gt;pons asinorum&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/Pons_Asinorum.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/Pons_Asinorum.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentary by Gisela Striker (2009, 195&amp;ndash;6):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, instead of building a helpful bridge, the diagram seems
to make Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s rules look much more complicated than they
are, because it also shows the cases in which no syllogisms can be
found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle first introduces the letters B , C, D and F, G, H to stand
for sets of terms, while A and E stand for the predicate- and subject­
terms of the desired conclusion. For both A and E there will be lists of
terms that either &#39; follow&#39; them ( B and F ) or are followed by the m (C
and G), or that cannot be predicated of them (D and H). Evidently, the
terms that are said to follow a given term are universally predicable
of it. The middle term in each case will be one that occurs in one of
the lists for A as well as one of the lists for E. In the first example,
Aristotle makes this explicit by speaking of &amp;lsquo;one of the Cs&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;one
of the Fs&amp;rsquo;; later on he simply uses the letters to stand for an item on
the respective list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ontology Aristotle presents in &lt;em&gt;Categories&lt;/em&gt; is complemented elsewhere in the &lt;em&gt;Organon&lt;/em&gt; with a sophisticated methodology for understanding and explaining beings and their attributes. (Most notably in the &lt;em&gt;Analytics&lt;/em&gt;, but also in the &lt;em&gt;Topics&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conspicuously &lt;em&gt;absent&lt;/em&gt; from this ontology and explanatory theory is a method for understanding and explaining &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt;, including both changes in the attributes belonging to substances and the coming to be of substances themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(N.B., considerations of change and coming to be are not wholly absent: see especially &lt;em&gt;APo.&lt;/em&gt; 2.12.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the &lt;em&gt;Organon&lt;/em&gt;, Aristotle will attempt to adapt this method and theory of explanation to accommodate explaining coming-to-be, but before he can do this, he has first to make conceptual sense of the phenomenon of change &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit 2 | Aristotle&#39;s Argument for Hylomorphism</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-dot-1-a-puzzle-about-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;2.1 | A Puzzle About Coming to Be&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physics 1.1, 185a13&amp;ndash;20 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, on the other hand, must take for granted that the things
that exist by nature are, either all or some of them, in
motion—which is indeed made plain by induction. Moreover,
no one is bound to solve every kind of difficulty that may be
[15] raised, but only as many as are drawn falsely from the
principles of the science: it is not our business to refute those
that do not arise in this way; just as it is the duty of the
geometer to refute the squaring of the circle by means of
segments, but it is not his duty to refute Antiphon’s proof. At
the same time the holders of the theory of which we are
speaking do incidentally raise physical questions, though
nature is not their subject; so it will perhaps be as well to
spend a few words on them, especially as [20] the inquiry is
not without scientific interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; I is devote to the subject of &amp;ldquo;principles&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;archai&lt;/em&gt; pl., &lt;em&gt;archē&lt;/em&gt;) of natural science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Archē&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;beginning, origin, source (e.g. of motion)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;principle-is-one&#34;&gt;Principle is one&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;either-motionless-dot-dot-dot&#34;&gt;Either motionless&amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmenides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[F8 ] . . . Only one tale is left of the way:
that it is; and on this are posted
very many signs, that [i] what-is is ungenerated and imperishable,
[ii] a whole of one kind, [iii] unperturbed and [iv] complete.
[i] Never was it, nor shall it be, since it now is, all together,
one, continuous. For what birth would you seek of it?
Where [or: how] , whence did it grow? Not from what-is-not will I
allow
you to say or to think; for it is not sayable or thinkable
that it is not. And what need would have stirred it
later or earlier, starting from nothing, to grow?
Thus it must be completely or not at all.
Nor ever from what-is-not will the strength of faith allow
anything to come to be beside it. Wherefore neither to come to be
nor to perish did Justice permit it by loosening its shackles,
but she holds it fast. And the decision concerning these things
comes to this:
it is or it is not. Thus the decision is made, as is necessary,
to leave the one way unthought, unnamed - for it is not a true
way - the other to be and to be true.
And how would what-is be hereafter? How would it have come
to be?
For if it has come to be, it is not, and similarly if it is ever about
ro k
Thus coming to be is quenched and perishing unheard of.
[ii] Nor is it divisible, since it is all alike,
nor is there any more here, which would keep it from holding
together,
nor any less, but it is all full of what-is.
Thus it is all continuous, for what-is cleaves to what-is.
[iii] Further, motionless in the limits of great bonds
it is without starting and stopping, since coming to be and
perishing
wandered very far away, and true faith banished them.
Remaining the same in the same by itself it lies
and thus it remains steadfast there; for mighty Necessity
holds it in the bonds of a limit, which confines it round about.
[iv] Wherefore it is not right for what-is to be incomplete;
for it is not needy; if it were&#39; it would lack everything.
The same thing is for thinking and is wherefore there is thought.
For not without what-is, to which it is directed,
will you find thought. For nothing else &amp;lt; either&amp;gt; i s nor shall be
beside what-is, since Fate shackled it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melissus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What-is (the principle) is one, and motionless, but &lt;em&gt;infinite&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dot-dot-dot-or-in-motion--physicists-phusiologoi&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip; Or in motion (&amp;ldquo;physicists&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em&gt;phusiologoi&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thales (everything is generated from water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anaximenes (everything is generated from air, though condensation and rarifaction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heraclitus (everything is fire)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;principles-are-more-than-one&#34;&gt;Principles are more than one&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;anaximander&#34;&gt;Anaximander&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All things come from &lt;em&gt;to apeiron&lt;/em&gt; (lit., the unbounded)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;empedocles&#34;&gt;Empedocles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One: the cosmos is in an eternal cycle of combination and separation, governed by the contrary principles Love and Strife&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many: everything comes about from the combination and separation of the four &amp;ldquo;roots&amp;rdquo;, earth, air, fire, and water, by Love and Strife&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[F20] I shall speak a double tale: at one time they grew to be one alone
from many, at another time it grew apart to be many from one.
Double is the birth of mortal things, and double the demise;
for the confluence of all things begets and destroys the one [generation] ,
while the other in turn, having been nurtured while things were
growing apart, fled away.
And these things never cease continually alternating,
at one time all coming together into one by Love,
at another time each being borne apart by the enmity of Strife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;anaxagoras&#34;&gt;Anaxagoras&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[F15] Everything else has a portion of everything, but mind is boundless,
autonomous, and mixed with no object, but it is alone all by itself. If it were
not by itself, but had been mixed with something else, it would have a portion
of all objects, if it had been mixed with any; for there is a portion of everything
in everything, as I said earlier [F12]. And the things mixed with it would hinder
it from ruling any object in the way it does when it is alone by itself. For it
is the finest of all objects and the purest, and it exercises complete oversight
over everything and prevails above all. And all things that have soul, both the
larger and the smaller, these does mind rule. And of the whole revolution did
mind take control, so that it revolved in the beginning. And first it began from
a small revolution, now it is revolving more, and it will revolve still more. And
things mixed together, things separated, and things segregated, all these did
mind comprehend. And the kinds of things that were to be - such as were but
now are not, all that now are, and such as will be - all these did mind set in
order, as well as this revolution, with which the stars, the sun, the moon, the
air, and the aether which were being separated now revolve. For this revolution
made things separate. And from the rare is separated the dense, from the cold
the hot, from the dark the bright, and from the wet the dry. But there are many
portions of many things. And nothing is completely separated nor segregated
the one from the other except mind. Mind is all alike, both the larger and the
smaller. No other thing is like anything else, but each one is and was most
manifestly those things of which it has the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminary-results-physics-1-dot-5-6&#34;&gt;Preliminary Results: &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.5&amp;ndash;6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming-to-be is always between &lt;em&gt;contraries&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, the number of the principles cannot be one, since there is no contrary to one&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the principles are either two or three, &amp;ldquo;but whether two or three is a question of considerable difficulty&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:EXPORT_FILE_NAME: unit2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-dot-2-a-solution-to-the-puzzles&#34;&gt;2.2 | A Solution to the Puzzles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics-1-dot-7&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aim of the chapter: to establish &amp;ldquo;the number and nature of the principles&amp;rdquo; of coming to be (&lt;em&gt;to genēsthai&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How?&lt;/em&gt; By analyzing the different ways in which things are &lt;em&gt;said&lt;/em&gt; to come to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;analysis-of-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;Analysis of Coming-to-Be&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 189b32&amp;ndash;34 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We say that ‘one thing comes to be from another thing, and something from something different&#39;, in the case both of simple and of complex things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. distinguishes 3 ways of characterizing a single episode of coming to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Socrates (the human being) becomes musical&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That which is not musical becomes musical&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Non-musical Socrates becomes musical Socrates&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Pass:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (1) and (2), both &amp;ldquo;that which becomes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;what it becomes&amp;rdquo; are &lt;strong&gt;simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (3), both &amp;ldquo;that which becomes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;what it becomes&amp;rdquo; are &lt;strong&gt;complex&lt;/strong&gt; (or &lt;strong&gt;combined&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;sunkeitai&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&amp;ldquo;That Which Becomes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&amp;ldquo;What It Becomes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Socrates&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Musical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Non-Musical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Musical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ldquo;Combined&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-Musical Socrates&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Musical Socrates&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple cases, in detail:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190a9&amp;ndash;13 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a simple thing is said to become something, in one case it survives [10] through the process, in the other it does not. For the man remains a man and is such even when he becomes musical, whereas what is not musical or is unmusical does not survive, either simply or combined with the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In which simple case of coming-to-be does &amp;ldquo;that which becomes&amp;rdquo; survive (lit., &amp;ldquo;remain, persist&amp;rdquo;; &lt;em&gt;hupomenon&lt;/em&gt;)?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer:
-   &lt;strong&gt;Socrates&lt;/strong&gt; survives coming to be musical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-   **The Non-Musical** does not survive coming to be musical.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;two-conditions-on-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;Two Conditions on Coming to Be&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190a13&amp;ndash;21 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These distinctions drawn, one can gather from surveying the various cases of becoming in the way we are describing that there must always be an underlying [15] something, namely that which becomes, and that this, though always one numerically, in form at least is not one. (By ‘in form’ I mean the same as ‘in account’.)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part survives, the other does not: what is not an opposite survives (for the man survives), but [20] not-musical or unmusical does not survive, nor does the compound of the two, namely the unmusical man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Subject Condition (SC)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In every case of coming to be, there must be some underlying subject, &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;, such that it is true &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; comes to be&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Persistance Condition (PC)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In every case of coming to be, the underlying subject must remain &lt;strong&gt;one in number&lt;/strong&gt;, although not &lt;strong&gt;one in form&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;logos&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cf. Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s account of numerical unity in &lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; Δ:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt; Δ 6, 1017a30&amp;ndash;34 (Ross tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, some things are one in number, others in species,
others in genus, others by analogy; in number those whose
matter is one, in species [= form] those whose formula is one, in genus
those to which the same figure of predication applies, by
analogy those which are related as a third thing is to a fourth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;varieties-of-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;Varieties of Coming to Be&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are said to come to be in different ways. In some cases we do not use the expression ‘come to be’, but ‘come to be so-and-so’. Only substances are said to come to be without qualification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Qualified Coming to Be&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; comes to be &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; (for some predicable &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; in a non-substance category)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Unqualified Coming to Be&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; comes to be (or: &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; comes to be &lt;em&gt;an F&lt;/em&gt;, for some kind of substance &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;applying-sc-and-pc&#34;&gt;Applying SC and PC&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject Condition applies to both qualified and unqualified coming to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190a33&amp;ndash;b5 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in all cases other than substance it is plain that there must be something underlying, namely, that which becomes. For when a thing comes to be of such a quantity or quality or in such a relation, time, or place, a subject is always [35] presupposed, since substance alone is not predicated of another subject, but everything else of substance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that substances too, and anything that can be said to be without [190 b 1] qualification, come to be from some underlying thing, will appear on examination. For we find in every case something that underlies from which proceeds that which comes to be; for instance, animals and plants from seed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What about PC?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualified Coming to Be:&lt;/strong&gt; Of course! It is the substance, or &lt;em&gt;tode ti&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190b24&amp;ndash;28 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the subject is one numerically, though it is two in form. (For there is the man, the gold—in general, the countable &lt;strong&gt;matter&lt;/strong&gt;; for it is more of the nature of a [25] ‘this’, and what comes to be does not come from it accidentally; the privation, on the other hand, and the contrariety are accidental.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Unqualified Coming to Be&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The &amp;ldquo;matter&amp;rdquo; of substance/subject of unqualified coming to be is knowable on analogy to the matter of qualified comings to be:&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 191a9&amp;ndash;12 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying nature can be known by analogy. For as the bronze is to the [10] statue, the wood to the bed, or the matter and the formless before receiving form to any thing which has form, so is the underlying nature to substance, i.e. the ‘this’ or existent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial formulation of &lt;strong&gt;matter&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.9, 192a31&amp;ndash;33 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my definition of matter is just this—the primary substratum of each thing, from which it comes to be, and which persists in the result, not accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;resolution-to-the-puzzle&#34;&gt;Resolution to the Puzzle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All coming to be is complex in that which comes to be:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190b11&amp;ndash;15 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, from what has been said, whatever comes to be is always complex. There is, on the one hand, something which comes to be, and again something which becomes that—the latter in two senses, either the subject or the opposite. By the opposite I mean the unmusical, by the subject, man; and similarly I call the absence of shape or form or order the opposite, and the bronze or stone or gold the [15] subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes to be is the &lt;strong&gt;Form&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;morphē&lt;/em&gt;), e.g. Musical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes to be is always a &amp;ldquo;compound&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;suntheton&lt;/em&gt;) involving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Subject&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;hupokeimenon&lt;/em&gt;), e.g. Socrates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Opposite&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Privation&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g. Non-Musical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, there are (depending on how one describes the coming to be) either two or three principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7, 190b29&amp;ndash;191a2 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a sense, therefore, in which we must declare the principles to be two, and a sense in which they are three; a sense in which the contraries are the [30] principles—say for example the musical and the unmusical, the hot and the cold, the tuned and the untuned—and a sense in which they are not, since it is impossible for the contraries to be acted on by each other. But this difficulty also is solved by the fact that what underlies is different from the contraries; for it is itself not a [35] contrary. The principles therefore are, in a way, not more in number than the contraries, but as it were two; nor yet precisely two, since there is a difference of [191 a 1] being, but three. For to be man is different from to be unmusical, and to be unformed from to be bronze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics-1-dot-8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.8&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Aim of the chapter&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;to show that &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; this analysis of coming to be can solve &amp;ldquo;the difficulty of the early thinkers, as well as our own&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-dilemmatic-argument&#34;&gt;A Dilemmatic Argument&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.8, 191a25&amp;ndash;31 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first of those who studied philosophy &amp;hellip; say that none of the things that are either comes to be or passes out of existence, because what comes to be must do so either from what is or from what is not, both of which are impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what is cannot come to be [30] (because it is already), and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from what is not nothing could have come to be (because something must be underlying).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; comes to be, it must come to be either&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from what is, or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; cannot come to be from what is, since what-is already &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; cannot come to be from what-is-not, since something must be underlying (SC, no generation &lt;em&gt;ex nihilo&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therefore&lt;/em&gt;, it is not the case that &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; comes to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-aristotelian-intervention&#34;&gt;The Aristotelian Intervention&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distinguish (1) coming to be from what is not &lt;em&gt;without qualification&lt;/em&gt; (which is impossible) from (2) coming to be from what is &lt;em&gt;not-F&lt;/em&gt;, where &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; is incidental to what something comes to be from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A doctor builds a house, not qua doctor, but qua housebuilder, and turns gray, not qua [5] doctor, but qua dark-haired. On the other hand he doctors or fails to doctor qua doctor. But we are using words most appropriately when we say that a doctor does something or undergoes something, or becomes something from being a doctor, if he does, undergoes, or becomes qua doctor. Clearly then also to come to be so-and-so from what is not means ‘qua what is not’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Qua&lt;/em&gt; Operator&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; does φ &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;qua F&lt;/span&gt; iff &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; does φ &lt;span class=&#34;underline&#34;&gt;in &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s capacity as (an) F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;responding-to-the-dilemma&#34;&gt;Responding to the Dilemma&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disarming the Second Horn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall: that which comes to be is complex, including both &lt;strong&gt;subject&lt;/strong&gt; (which survives as a constituent of that which comes to be) and &lt;strong&gt;privation&lt;/strong&gt; (which is something which is not and does not survive).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.8, 191b13&amp;ndash;17 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ourselves are in agreement with them in holding that nothing can be said without qualification to come from what is not. But nevertheless we maintain that a thing may come to be from what is not in a qualified sense, i.e. accidentally. For a [15] thing comes to be from the privation, which in its own nature is something which is not—this not surviving as a constituent of the result. Yet this causes surprise, and it is thought impossible that something should come to be in the way described from what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disarming the First Horn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall: the subject in every case comes to be &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt; from being &lt;em&gt;not-F&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.8, 191b17&amp;ndash;25 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way we maintain that nothing comes to be from what is, and that what is does not come to be except accidentally. In that way, however, it does, just as animal might come to be from animal, and an animal of a certain kind from an animal of a certain kind. Thus, suppose a dog to come to be from a dog, or a horse [20] from a horse. The dog would then, it is true, come to be from animal (as well as from an animal of a certain kind) but not as animal, for that is already there. But if anything is to become an animal, not accidentally, it will not be from animal; and if what is, not from what is—nor from what is not either, for it has been explained that [25] by ‘from what is not’ we mean qua what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lingering-questions&#34;&gt;Lingering Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Details of Unqualified Coming to Be&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What is the subject of substantial generation? What is the relevant privation? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it the case that substances lacks contraries (&lt;em&gt;Cat.&lt;/em&gt; 5)?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;A Puzzling Reference&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A. claims that the same dilemma has been solved elsewhere in terms of &lt;strong&gt;potentiality&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;dunamis&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;actuality&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;energeia&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;Where, and how?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.8, 191b27&amp;ndash;29 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This then is one way of solving the difficulty. Another consists in pointing out that the same things can be spoken of in terms of potentiality and actuality. But this has been done with greater precision elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-dot-3-substantial-vs-dot-non-substantial-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;2.3 | Substantial vs. Non-Substantial Coming to Be&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-notions&#34;&gt;Basic Notions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;kinds-of-coming-to-be-passing-away&#34;&gt;Kinds of Coming to Be/Passing Away&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Coming-to-be/generation&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;to genēsthai&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;genesis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Passing away/corruption&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;phthora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cf. &lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.4, 319b30&amp;ndash;320a2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth/Diminution:&lt;/strong&gt; Change of contraries (&lt;em&gt;metabolē tēs enantōseōs&lt;/em&gt;) in the category of quantity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locomotion:&lt;/strong&gt; Change of contraries in the category of place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alteration:&lt;/strong&gt; Change in the category of &amp;ldquo;affection (&lt;em&gt;pathos&lt;/em&gt;) and quality&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unqualified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generation/Destruction:&lt;/strong&gt; Change in which &amp;ldquo;nothing persists of which the other is generally an affection or accident&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is this account of unqualified coming to be consistent with the &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1 account? Recall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject Condition (SC):&lt;/strong&gt; In every case of coming to be, there must be some underlying subject, &lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;, such that it is true &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; comes to be&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistance Condition (PC):&lt;/strong&gt; In every case of coming to be, the underlying subject must remain &lt;strong&gt;one in number&lt;/strong&gt;, although not &lt;strong&gt;one in form&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;logos&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;basics-of-aristotelian-mereology&#34;&gt;Basics of Aristotelian Mereology&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Elements&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;That into which all bodies are ultimately divided, but which are not themselves divided into anything different in kind (&lt;em&gt;Metaph.&lt;/em&gt; 1014a32&amp;ndash;35)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Homoiomeres&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Lit. &amp;ldquo;same-parts&amp;rdquo;; compound bodies of which the parts are the same in kind as the whole (e.g. flesh, bone, sinew, blood)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Functional Parts (&lt;em&gt;organa&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Compound bodies defined in terms of their function, and whose parts are not the same in kind as the whole (e.g., nose, hand)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Substances&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Compound bodies not present in anything else as part.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;transformation-of-the-elements&#34;&gt;Transformation of the Elements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Sublunary Aristotelian Simple Bodies (≈ Elements)&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Earth, Air, Fire, Water&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Primary Differentia of Simple Bodies&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Hot and Cold, Wet and Dry
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire:&lt;/strong&gt; Hot + Dry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Air:&lt;/strong&gt; Hot + Moist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water:&lt;/strong&gt; Cold + Moist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earth:&lt;/strong&gt; Cold + Dry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reciprocal Transformation of the Elements&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The coming to be of the elemental bodies is cyclical, effected by a replacement of a single pair of contraries between one element and the other.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air comes to be from Fire by the replacement of Dry with Moist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water comes to be from Air by the replacement of Cold with Hot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth comes to be from Water by the replacement of Moist with Dry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fire comes to be from Earth by the replacement of Cold with Hot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;!--listend--&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Is elemental transformation possible without &lt;strong&gt;prime matter&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tasks-of-gc-1-dot-1-4&#34;&gt;The Tasks of &lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.1&amp;ndash;4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.1, 314a1&amp;ndash;5 (Williams tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our task now is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to pick out the causes and definitions of generation and corruption common to all those things which come to be and perish in the course of nature; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;secondly to investigate growth and alteration, asking what each of them is, and whether we are to suppose that the nature of alteration and generation is the same or different, as they are certainly distinguished in name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.1&amp;ndash;3 are concerned principally with Task 1, specifically with articulating a basic account of unqualified generation and corruption&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GC 1.4&amp;ndash;5 are concerned principally with Task 2, distinguishing unqualified generation from both alteration and growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is Task 2 so pressing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As A. tells us at the end of &lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.2 317a17&amp;ndash;26 (Williams tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, coming to be simpliciter, i.e. absolutely, is not defined by aggregation and segregation, as some say; nor is change in what is continuous the same as alteration. This is just where all the mistakes are made. Coming to be and ceasing to be simpliciter occur, not in virtue of aggregation and segregation, but when something changes from this to that as a whole. These people think that all such change is alteration, but there is in fact a distinction. &lt;strong&gt;For within the substratum there is something which corresponds to the definition and something which corresponds to the matter. When, therefore, the change takes place in these it will be generation or corruption: when it takes place in the affections, accidentally, it will be alteration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-basic-model-of-generation-in-gc-1-dot-1-3&#34;&gt;The Basic Model of Generation in &lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.1&amp;ndash;3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answers 2 questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is generation/corruption without qualification (or absolutely, or &lt;em&gt;simpliciter&lt;/em&gt;)? Why is it that some coming to be is absolute, while some is not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.3, 317b12&amp;ndash;34 (Williams tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dilemmas that arise concerning these matters and their solutions have been set out at greater length elsewhere, but it should now again be said by way of summary that in one way it is from what is not that a thing comes to be simpliciter, though in another way it is always from what is; for that which is potentially but is not actually must pre-exist, being described in both these ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even when these distinctions have been made, there remains a question of remarkable difficulty, which we must take up once again, namely, how is coming to be simpliciter possible, whether from what is potentially or some other way. One might well wonder whether there is coming to be of substance and the individual, as opposed to quality, quantity, and place (and the same question arises in the case of ceasing to be). For if something comes to be, clearly there will exist potentially, not actually, some substance from which the coming to be will arise and into which that which ceases to be has to change. Now will any of the others belong to this actually?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is: Will that which is only potentially individual and existent, but neither individual nor existent simpliciter, have any quality or quanity or place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it has none of these, but all of them potentially, (a) that which in this sense is not will consequently be separable, and further, (b) the principal and perpetual fear of the early philosophers will be realized, namely, the coming to be of something from nothing previously existing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if being individual and a substance are not going to belong to it while some of the other things we have mentioned are, the affections will, as we have remarked, be separable from the substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is unqualified generation/corruption, why does it persist? Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the total quantity of bodies continually shrink into non-existence?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.3, 318b33&amp;ndash;319a3 (Williams tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now stated the reason why there is such a thing as generation simpliciter, which is the corruption of something, and such a thing as corruption simpliciter, which is the generation of something: it is due to a difference of matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;either in respect of its being substance or not being substance,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or in respect of its being more or less so,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or because in the one case the matter from which or to which the change takes place is more perceptible and in the other case less perceptible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;How does this account of absolute generation apply to the transformation of the elements?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;distinguishing-absolute-generation-from-alteration--gc-1-dot-4&#34;&gt;Distinguishing Absolute Generation from Alteration (&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.4)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.4, 319b8&amp;ndash;21 (Williams tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The substratum is one thing and the affection whose nature is to be predicated of the substratum another, and either of them can change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Alteration&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;So it is alteration when the substratum remains, being something perceptible [i.e., a &lt;em&gt;tode ti&lt;/em&gt; or individual] but change occurs in the affections which belong to it, whether these are contraries or intermediates. For example, the body is well then ill, but remains the same body; the bronze is now round, now a thing with corners, but remains the same [sc. bronze].&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Generation&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;When, however, the whole changes without anything perceptible remaining as the same substratum, but the way:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the seed changes entirely into blood,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;water into air,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or air entirely into water,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then, when we have this sort of thing, it is a case of generation (and corrpution of something else); particularly if the change takes place from what is imperceptible to what is perceptible either by touch or by the other senses, as when water is generated or corrupts into air, since air is&amp;mdash;near enough&amp;mdash;imperceptible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these cases [sc. of generation] if some affection that is one of a pair of contraries remains the same in the thing generated as it was in the thing that has perished, e.g. when water comes from air, if both are transparent or &amp;lt;wet, but not&amp;gt; cold, this must not have the other, the terminus of the change, as an affection of itself. Otherwise it will be alteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/subject-formmatter.png&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.roberthowton.com/ox-hugo/subject-formmatter.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-unqualified-nature-of-elemental-transformations&#34;&gt;The Unqualified Nature of Elemental Transformations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 1.4, 319b21&amp;ndash;31 (RFH rough tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ἐν δὲ τούτοις ἄν τι ὑπομένῃ πάθος τὸ αὐτὸ ἐναντιώ
σεως ἐν τῷ γενομένῳ καὶ τῷ φθαρέντι, οἷον ὅταν ἐξ ἀέρος
ὕδωρ, εἰ ἄμφω διαφανῆ ἢ ψυχρά, οὐ δεῖ τούτου θάτερον
πάθος εἶναι εἰς ὃ μεταβάλλει. Εἰ δὲ μή, ἔσται ἀλλοίωσις,
[25] οἷον ὁ μουσικὸς ἄνθρωπος ἐφθάρη, ἄνθρωπος δ&#39; ἄμουσος ἐγέ-
νετο, ὁ δ&#39; ἄνθρωπος ὑπομένει τὸ αὐτό.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Εἰ μὲν οὖν τούτου μὴ
πάθος ἦν καθ&#39; αὑτὸ ἡ μουσικὴ καὶ ἡ ἀμουσία, τοῦ μὲν γένε-
σις ἦν ἄν, τοῦ δὲ φθορά· διὸ ἀνθρώπου μὲν ταῦτα πάθη,
ἀνθρώπου δὲ μουσικοῦ καὶ ἀνθρώπου ἀμούσου γένεσις καὶ
[30] φθορά· νῦν δὲ πάθος τοῦτο τοῦ ὑπομένοντος. Διὸ ἀλλοίωσις τὰ
τοιαῦτα.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I] In those things in which some affection from among a pair of contraries remains the same in both what comes to be and what is destroyed&amp;mdash;for instance, when water [comes to be] from air, assuming both are transparent or &lt;del&gt;cold&lt;/del&gt; [moist?]&amp;mdash;the other, into which it changes, must not be an affection of it. If it is, it will be [a case of] alteration, as [when] the musical person perishes and the unmusical person comes to be, the person remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[II] &lt;strong&gt;Hence if &lt;em&gt;musical&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unmusical&lt;/em&gt; were not &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt; affections of this [sc. the person], we would have generation of the latter and passing away of the former.&lt;/strong&gt; This is why they are affections of a person, whereas of &lt;em&gt;musical person&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unmusical person&lt;/em&gt; we have generation and destruction. As it is, however, this is an affection of what remains, for which reason [transformations] of this sort are [cases of] alteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Upshot of [I]&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;On pain of being cases of alteration, it cannot be supposed that the persisting subject of elemental transformations is the quality that inheres in both what comes to be and what perishes.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Upshot of [II]&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Despite the superficial similarity in the locutions (1) &amp;ldquo;the musical person comes to be the unmusical person&amp;rdquo; and (2) &amp;ldquo;the hot moist comes to be the cold moist&amp;rdquo;, they describe two ontologically distinct changes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (1), the affections &lt;em&gt;musical&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unmusical&lt;/em&gt; are affections of the person &lt;em&gt;as such&lt;/em&gt;, which therefore persists through the alteration as subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In (2), however, the affections &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;cold&lt;/em&gt; are affections of the moist only &lt;em&gt;incidentally&lt;/em&gt;, in the way the pale thing (the person who happens to be pale) is musical or unmusical. Hence it is wrong to suppose that the moist is a subject of predication, much less that it persists through the transition from hot to cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-interpretive-strategies--pros-and-cons&#34;&gt;Two Interpretive Strategies (Pros and Cons)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What, if anything, is the subject of which &lt;em&gt;moist&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hot&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;cold&lt;/em&gt; are predicated?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First air, then water:&lt;/strong&gt; Coheres with A.&amp;rsquo;s denial of a persistent subject in unqualified generation, but at the cost of treating elemental transformation (and all substantial coming-to-be) as a process of &amp;ldquo;sheer replacement&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prime matter:&lt;/strong&gt; Avoids the &amp;ldquo;sheer replacement&amp;rdquo; model, and perhaps enjoys some textual support, but the metaphysical victory is pyrrhic: what sort of improvement is it to say that water comes to be from pure potentiality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit 3 | Natural Substances as Hylomorphic Compounds</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 17:16:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course-hylomorphism/lectures/unit3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-dot-1-nature-and-causation&#34;&gt;3.1 | Nature &amp;amp; Causation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unity of Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; is a matter of scholarly controversy, but it seems clear that &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2&amp;ndash;4 (at least) constitute a continuous discussion of &lt;strong&gt;nature&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;phusis&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2 provides the foundation of this discussion, defending a definition of nature as well as an enumeration of the kinds of cause operative in the things that come about by or in accordance with nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-division-among-beings&#34;&gt;A Division Among Beings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1 begins with a distinction among beings (&lt;em&gt;ta onta&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 192b8&amp;ndash;23 (RFH quasi-literal translation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the things that are (&lt;em&gt;ta onta&lt;/em&gt;), some are by nature (&lt;em&gt;phusei&lt;/em&gt;), while others are due to other causes (&lt;em&gt;aitia&lt;/em&gt;). By nature are animals and their parts; plants; and simple bodies like earth, fire, air, and water (for we say that these and things like them are by nature); and all of these plainly differ from those things which are not constituted by nature. &lt;strong&gt;For each of these [which are constituted by nature] has in itself a principle (&lt;em&gt;archē&lt;/em&gt;) of change and rest, some [a principle of change] in respect of place, some in respect of growth and decay, and some in respect of alteration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, a bed, or cloak, or anything else of that sort does not have an innate impulse for change, [at least] not &lt;em&gt;qua&lt;/em&gt; satisfying these descriptions and to the extent that they are products of craft (&lt;em&gt;technē&lt;/em&gt;). However, insofar as they are made of stone or earth, or a mixture of the two, to that extent they do [have an innate impulse for change], since &lt;strong&gt;nature is a kind of principle and cause of changing and resting in that to which it belongs primarily, in virtue of itself and not accidentally&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here Aristotle divides &lt;em&gt;ta onta&lt;/em&gt; (exhaustively?) into two kinds:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those that are (what they are) by nature, which, as the sort of things they are, have an internal causal principle of change and rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those that are (what they are) not by nature, which do not, as the sort of things they are, have an internal causal principle of change and rest, but come about from other causes (e.g., craft).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nature-as-a-principle-of-change&#34;&gt;Nature as a Principle of Change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What distinguishes things that are by nature from things that are due to other causes (including craft) is the presence of a certain &lt;em&gt;internal&lt;/em&gt; cause and source of change and rest, which Aristotle identifies as &lt;strong&gt;nature&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Nature&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;A causal source (principle) of change/rest internal to what it belongs to primarily &lt;em&gt;in virtue of itself (per se), i.e. not accidentally&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The qualification &lt;em&gt;in virtue of itself&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;non-accidentally&lt;/em&gt; refers to the connection between what is said to be &amp;ldquo;by nature&amp;rdquo; and what the nature in question is said to be predicated of:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 192b23&amp;ndash;32 (RFH quasi-literal translation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean by &amp;ldquo;not accidentally&amp;rdquo; that, for instance, although a doctor might be a cause of health in himself, he nevertheless has skill in medicine not to the extent that he is healed; rather, the doctor just &lt;em&gt;happens&lt;/em&gt; to be the same as the person who is healed. Indeed, this is why the two [sc. doctor and patient] can be separated from one another. Circumstances are similar with each of the other things that have been made: none of them have the source of production in themselves. Rather, for some [the cause] is present in other things and comes from without, such as a house and other handmade products, while for others it is present in themselves but not in virtue of themselves&amp;mdash;whatever comes to be a cause of itself accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questions-for-aristotle-s-definition&#34;&gt;Questions for Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s definition:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the order of explanation between the division of beings and the definition of nature? Do we take the division as given and posit the presence of nature to explain it, or is it the other way around? (Cf. 193a3 ff.: &amp;ldquo;That there is such as thing as nature would be ludicrous to try to show&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For A., nature is a &amp;ldquo;causal principle&amp;rdquo;, both an &lt;em&gt;archē&lt;/em&gt; and a cause (&lt;em&gt;aition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;aitia&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does nature (understood as an &lt;em&gt;archē&lt;/em&gt;) relate to the &lt;em&gt;archai&lt;/em&gt; of natural beings discussed in &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 293b18&amp;ndash;21 (RFH tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, both form and nature are double, since privation too is in a way form. But whether or not privation and opposition of a sort are concerned with unqualified generation, we will have to inquire later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does nature operate as a cause? (Cf. &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.3: cause is said in many ways&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nature-as-form-and-matter&#34;&gt;Nature as Form and Matter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One step toward answering these questions is to observe that, in &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, A. identifies nature with both &lt;em&gt;substance-&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;subjecthood&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nature-as-substance-and-subject&#34;&gt;Nature as Substance and Subject&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 192b32&amp;ndash;34 (RFH quasi-literal translation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature, then, is what we said, and everything that has such as principle has a nature. All of these, moreover, are substances (&lt;em&gt;ousiai&lt;/em&gt;), since each is a kind of subject (&lt;em&gt;hupokeimenon ti&lt;/em&gt;), and nature is always present in a subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nature-as-matter&#34;&gt;Nature as Matter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because all nature is present in a subject, and (as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen) matter is a subject, it is only natural to suppose that the nature of each thing corresponds to its &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 193a9&amp;ndash;17 (RFH rough trans.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature and substance of things in which nature is present seem to be that which exists primary in each, &lt;namely what is&gt; unformed in virtue of itself, [so that] for instance wood would be the nature of a bed and bronze of a statue. As a sign of this Antiphon says that if you bury a bed and the rotting wood acquired the capacity (&lt;em&gt;dunamis&lt;/em&gt;) to send up a shoot, what would come about would not be a bed but wood, which shows that what exists accidentally is the arrangment according to convention and craft [sc. the bed], but the substance is the other [sc. the wood], which also remains continuously and suffers these [changes in arrangement].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As A. makes clear, this line of reasoning terminates in the conclusion that the elements are the nature of things, for if wood is the nature of the bed, and wood stands (e.g.) to earth as the bed to the wood, then earth would be the nature of wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 193a22&amp;ndash;28 (Charlton tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence fire, earth, air, and water have been held to be the nature of things, some people choosing just one for this role, some several, and some making use of all. Those who fix on some such element or elements represent it or them as the entire reality, and say that other things are merely affections, states, or dispositions; and these elements are all held to be imperishable in that they do not change out of themselves, whilst other things come to be and pass away as often as you please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nature-as-form&#34;&gt;Nature as Form&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For A., however, nature can &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; refer to the form (&lt;em&gt;morphē&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;logos&lt;/em&gt; of each thing. Aristotle offers three arguments for this conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analogy with the Products of Craft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 193a28&amp;ndash;b5 (Charlton tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is one way of using the word &amp;ldquo;nature&amp;rdquo;: for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the primary underlying matter in each case, of things which have in themselves a source of their movements and changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also used for the shape and form which accords with a thing&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Argument for 2]&lt;/strong&gt; Just as that which is in accordance with art and artificial is called art, so that which is in accordance with nature and natural is called nature. And as in the one case we would not yet say that a thing is at all in accordance with art, or that it is [in accordance with] art, if it is a bed only in possibility, and has not yet the form of a bed, so with things constituted naturally: that which is flesh or bone only in possibility, before it acquires the form which accords with the account by which we define what flesh or bone is, does not yet have its proper nature, and is not a thing due to nature. So there is another way of speaking, according to which nature is the shape and form of things which have in themselves a source of their changes, something which is not separable except in respect of its account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument proceeds as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P1
: We use &amp;ldquo;nature&amp;rdquo; in the same way that we use &amp;ldquo;art&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;craft&amp;rdquo;, &lt;em&gt;technē&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P2
: We say things are (what they are) in accordance with art only when they &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; possess the form imposed on them by the relevant art.
-   &lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Wood that is &lt;em&gt;potentially&lt;/em&gt; a bed is not yet in accordance with art; only when it &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; has the form of a bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C
: &lt;em&gt;So&lt;/em&gt;, by analogy, we say things are (what they are) in accordance with nature only when they &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; possess &amp;ldquo;the form which accords with the account by which we define&amp;rdquo; what it is.
-   &lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; What is &lt;em&gt;potentially&lt;/em&gt; flesh or bone is not yet in accordance with nature [= the nature of flesh/bone?]; only when it &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; has the relevant form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parity of Reasoning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As A. suggests in the previous argument, nature is also &amp;ldquo;the shape and form of things which have in themselves a source of their changes, something which is not separable except in respect of its account&amp;rdquo; (on which see &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.2). With the next argument, A. begins to make clear in what sense form can operate as a source of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument attempts to argue by &lt;strong&gt;parity of reasoning&lt;/strong&gt; with Antiphon&amp;rsquo;s bed argument earlier in the chapter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 193b8&amp;ndash;12 (RFH tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a human comes to be from a human, but not a bed from a bed. This is also why people say the shape is not nature but rather the wood, because if it grew it would not be a bed that came to be but wood. Hence if this is nature, so too must the form be nature, since human comes from human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature as End of Change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In different ways, then, both nature-as-form and nature-as-matter seem to have a causal role in the origin and source of natural changes. Additionally, nature-as-form has a role to play as the end towards which a natural change proceeds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1, 193b&amp;ndash;18 (RFH tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, nature spoken of as coming-to-be is a path into nature (&lt;em&gt;hodos eis phusis&lt;/em&gt;). This is not like the practice of medicine, which is said to be a path, not into medicine, but to health. The reason is that the practice of medicine must not proceed to medicine, but from it, whereas nature does not stand to nature in this way. To the contrary, what grows, &lt;em&gt;qua&lt;/em&gt; growing, proceeds from something into something. What, then, is it that grows? It is not that from which, but rather that into which, it grows. Therefore form is nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note
: &amp;ldquo;nature&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;phusis&lt;/em&gt;) derives from the Greek word for &amp;ldquo;grow&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;phuein&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. makes this point a bit more clearly in &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;194a28&amp;ndash;33 (RFH rough tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature is an end (&lt;em&gt;telos&lt;/em&gt;) and that for the sake of which (&lt;em&gt;hou heneka&lt;/em&gt;), for when in a continuous change there is some end, this [sc. the end] is the last and that for the sake of which. For this reason too the poet was ridiculous to say &amp;ldquo;he has reached the end for whose sake he was born&amp;rdquo;. For not everything which is last should be considered the end, but rather the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nature-as-cause&#34;&gt;Nature as Cause&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For A., then, nature, understood as a principle of change, is &amp;ldquo;double&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;dichōs&lt;/em&gt;), both form and matter. The two senses, however, are not equal, since for A. form must be considered &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; nature than matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;193b6&amp;ndash;8 (RFH tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This [sc. form, morphē?] is nature rather than the matter. For each thing is more property said [to be what it is] when it is actually, rather than potentially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this double conception of nature reflected in A.&amp;rsquo;s idea that nature is a kind of &lt;em&gt;cause&lt;/em&gt;? To answer this question, we need to turn to &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.3, where A. outlines the different ways in which things are said to be a cause (&lt;em&gt;aitios&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;aition&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.3, 194b23&amp;ndash;195a3 (Charlton tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to one way of speaking, that out of which as a constituent a thing comes to be is called a cause; for example, the bronze and the silver and their genera would be the causes respectively of a statue and a loving-cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to another, the form or model is a cause; this is the account of what the being would be, and its genera—thus the cause of an octave is the ratio of two to one, and more generally number—and the parts which come into the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, there is the primary source of the change or the staying unchanged: for example, the man who has deliberated is a cause, the father is a cause of the child, and in general that which makes something of that which is made, and that which changes something of that which is changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again, a thing may be a cause as the end. That is what something is for, as health might be what a walk is for. On account of what does he walk? We answer &amp;lsquo;To keep fit&amp;rsquo; and think that, in saying that, we have given the cause. And anything which, the change being effected by something else, comes to be on the way to the end, as slimness, purging, drugs, and surgical instruments come to be as means to health: all these are for the end, but differ in that the former are works [or functions, &lt;em&gt;erga&lt;/em&gt; ] and the latter tools [ &lt;em&gt;organa&lt;/em&gt; ].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How nature-as-form and nature-as-matter map on to the notion of &lt;em&gt;cause&lt;/em&gt; in these senses is an important question for the remainder of &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2. We&amp;rsquo;ll pick up with it next Thursday, and then again next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-dot-2-necessity-and-teleology&#34;&gt;3.2 | Necessity &amp;amp; Teleology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Nature is an internal causal principle of change and rest in that which is by nature primarily and non-accidentally.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;What kind of causal principle?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Answer&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s complicated&amp;hellip;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1&amp;ndash;2:&lt;/strong&gt; Nature is &amp;ldquo;double&amp;rdquo;, both formal and material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.3:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Cause&amp;rdquo; is said in many ways: formal, material, efficient, and final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;drawing-conclusions&#34;&gt;Drawing Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.7 A. consolidates some of these conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.7, 198a22&amp;ndash;31 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the causes being four, it is the business of the student of nature to know about them all, and if he refers his problems back to all of them, he will assign the ‘why’ in the way proper to his science—the matter, the form, the mover, that for the [25] sake of which. &lt;strong&gt;The last three often coincide; for the what and that for the sake of which are one, while the primary source of motion is the same in species as these.&lt;/strong&gt; For man generates man—and so too, in general, with all things which cause movement by being themselves moved; and such as are not of this kind are no longer inside the province of natural science, for they cause motion not by possessing motion or a source of motion in themselves, but being themselves incapable of [30] motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The form, mover, and that for the sake of which are, in many cases, operations of &lt;strong&gt;formal nature&lt;/strong&gt; in natural substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice, however, that matter too can operate as a source of motion, as when we say that something is heated due to the presence of fire. In natural substances (a plant or animal, say) these sorts of efficient causes cannot &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; be attributed to formal nature but rather &lt;strong&gt;material nature&lt;/strong&gt;. How do these two types of cause interact in nature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering this question is the topic of &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8&amp;ndash;9, which Aristotle devotes to arguing for two claims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;nature belongs to the class of causes that act for the sake of something&amp;rdquo; (198b9&amp;ndash;10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.9:&lt;/strong&gt; The place of (material) necessity in nature, &amp;ldquo;for all writers ascribe things to this cause, arguing that since the hot and the cold and the like are of such and such a kind, therefore certain things necessarily are and come to be—and if they mention any other cause (one friendship and strife, [15] another mind), it is only to touch on it, and then good-bye to it&amp;rdquo; (198b10&amp;ndash;15).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nature-as-a-final-cause&#34;&gt;Nature as a Final Cause&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Observation&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Some things in nature do not happen for the sake of anything, &lt;em&gt;even though it benefits something&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the farmer benefits from the rain, it does not rain &lt;em&gt;for the sake of&lt;/em&gt; making the corn grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the tourism industry in Antalya benefits from sunny summer weather, the weather is not sunny &lt;em&gt;for the sake of&lt;/em&gt; the tourism industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; natural processes happen this way?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8, 16&amp;ndash;32 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A difficulty presents itself: why should not nature work, not for the sake of something, nor because it is better so, but just as the sky rains, not in order to make the corn grow, but of necessity? (What is drawn up must cool, and what has been cooled must become water and descend, the result of this being that the corn grows.) [20] Similarly if a man’s crop is spoiled on the threshing-floor, the rain did not fall for the sake of this—in order that the crop might be spoiled—but that result just followed. Why then should it not be the same with the parts in nature, e.g. that our teeth should come up of necessity—the front teeth sharp, fitted for tearing, the [25] molars broad and useful for grinding down the food—since they did not arise for this end, but it was merely a coincident result; and so with all other parts in which we suppose that there is purpose? Wherever then all the parts came about just what they would have been if they had come to be for an end, such things survived, being [30] organized spontaneously in a fitting way; whereas those which grew otherwise perished and continue to perish, as Empedocles says his ‘man-faced oxprogeny’ did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;aristotle-s-principal-argument-for-natural-teleology&#34;&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Principal Argument for Natural Teleology&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8, 198b32&amp;ndash;199a8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it is impossible that this should be the true view. For teeth and all other natural things either invariably or for the most part come about in a given way; but of not one of the results of chance or spontaneity is this true. We do not [199a1] ascribe to chance or mere coincidence the frequency of rain in winter, but frequent rain in summer we do; nor heat in summer but only if we have it in winter. If then, it is agreed that things are either the result of coincidence or for the sake of something, and these cannot be the result of coincidence or spontaneity, it follows [5] that they must be for the sake of something; and that such things are all due to nature even the champions of the theory which is before us would agree. Therefore action for an end is present in things which come to be and are by nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A (very) rough reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P1
: For any product of nature, &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt;, either &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about by chance or &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about for the sake of something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P2
: If &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about by nature, then &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about (in the way it does) either always or for the most part (i.e. if nothing external interferes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P3
: Nothing that happens always or for the most part comes about by chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C
: So, if &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about by nature, then &lt;em&gt;o&lt;/em&gt; comes about for the sake of something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplement: Aristotle on Chance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. here seems to be relying on &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.4&amp;ndash;6, which argued that chance and spontaneity are distinct sorts of cause, in particular on this observation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.5, 196b1&amp;ndash;16 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First then we observe that some things always come to pass in the same [10] way, and others for the most part. It is clearly of neither of these that chance, or the result of chance, is said to be the cause—neither of that which is by necessity and always, nor of that which is for the most part. But as there is a third class of events besides these two—events which all say are by chance—it is plain that there is such [15] a thing as chance and spontaneity; for we know that things of this kind are due to chance and that things due to chance are of this kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle reiterates this observation in &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8 (199b16&amp;ndash;26, Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those things are natural which, by a continuous movement originated from an internal principle, arrive at some end: the same end is not reached from every principle; nor any chance end, but always the tendency in each is towards the same end, if there is no impediment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end and the means towards it may come about by chance. We say, for instance, that a stranger has come by chance, paid the ransom, and gone away, [20] when he does so as if he had come for that purpose, though it was not for that that he came. This is accidental, for chance is an accidental cause, as I remarked before. But when an event takes place always or for the most part, it is not accidental or by [25] chance. In natural products the sequence is invariable, if there is no impediment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions for Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Argument&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might not A. be begging the question against his opponents? (More on this Thursday)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-craft-analogy&#34;&gt;The Craft Analogy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s conception of natural teleology relies on an important analogy with art (or craft, &lt;em&gt;technē&lt;/em&gt;), which in his view always operates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either to bring to completion what nature has not finished, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imitates nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8, 199a17&amp;ndash;18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, therefore, artificial products are for the sake of an end, so clearly are natural products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s the analogy is strict: apart from the fact that the causes of artificial products are external to the products themselves, art and nature are purposive in the same way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8, 199b26&amp;ndash;30 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is absurd to suppose that purpose is not present because we do not observe the agent deliberating. Art does not deliberate. If the ship-building art were in the wood, it would produce the same results by nature. If, therefore, purpose is present in art, it is present also in nature. The best illustration is a doctor doctoring himself: [30] nature is like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-kinds-of-necessity&#34;&gt;Two Kinds of Necessity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.8, Aristotle associated form with &amp;ldquo;the cause in the sense of that for the sake of which&amp;rdquo; (199a30&amp;ndash;33).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, when Aristotle turns to the role of necessity (&lt;em&gt;anankē&lt;/em&gt;) in nature, he argues for a subordinate causal role for material nature in natural processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, however, he has to clarify the sense in which it is true to say that things happen &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; in nature. Again he relies on an analogy with craft:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 199b33&amp;ndash;200a14 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current view places what is of necessity in the process of production, just as if one were to suppose that the wall of a house [200a1] necessarily comes to be because what is heavy is naturally carried downwards and what is light to the top, so that the stones and foundations take the lowest place, with earth above because it is lighter, and wood at the top of all as being the lightest. Whereas, though the wall does not come to be without these, it is not due to these, [5] except as its material cause: it comes to be for the sake of sheltering and guarding certain things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly in all other things which involve that for the sake of which: the product cannot come to be without things which have a necessary nature, but it is not due to these (except as its material); it comes to be for an end. For instance, why is a saw such as it is? To effect so-and-so and for the sake of so-and-so. This [10] end, however, cannot be realized unless the saw is made of iron. It is, therefore, necessary for it to be of iron, if we are to have a saw and perform the operation of sawing. &lt;strong&gt;What is necessary then, is necessary on a hypothesis, not as an end. Necessity is in the matter, while that for the sake of which is in the definition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Observation&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It seems that we can explain a number of natural processes by focusing only on the necessary (efficient causal) effects of matter, e.g. heatings and coolings, hardenings and softenings, etc.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Question&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this make the role of formal nature as a final cause &lt;em&gt;redundant&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Answer&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;No! All that happens &amp;ldquo;of necessity&amp;rdquo; in these natural processes is conditional on a hypothesis, namely: that there is to be an &lt;em&gt;F&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 200a24&amp;ndash;29 (Hardie and Gaye tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If then there is to be a house, such-and-such things must be made or be there already or exist, or generally [25] the matter relative to the end, bricks and stones if it is a house. But the end is not due to these except as the matter, nor will it come to exist because of them. Yet if they do not exist at all, neither will the house, or the saw—the former in the absence of stones, the latter in the absence of iron&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cause &lt;em&gt;sine qua non&lt;/em&gt; (without which not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-dot-3-a-hylomorphic-model-of-animal-generation&#34;&gt;3.3 | A Hylomorphic Model of Animal Generation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gc-2-dot-9-return-to-the-number-and-nature-of-the-principles-of-coming-to-be&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9 | Return to the Number and Nature of the Principles of Coming-to-Be&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 1.7&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The principles of coming to be are three - form, privation, and subject.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;Physics&lt;/em&gt; 2.1&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;These principles can be consigned to matter (subject) and form (form and privation).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;There is a third principle &amp;ldquo;present over and above&amp;rdquo; matter and form&amp;hellip;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335a28&amp;ndash;32 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principles, then, are equal in number to, and identical in
kind with, those in the sphere of the eternal and primary
things. For there is one in the sense of matter, and a second in
the sense of form; and, in addition, the third must be present
[30] as well. For the two are not sufficient to bring things into
being, any more than they are adequate to account for the
primary things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;against-purely-material-explanations-of-generation&#34;&gt;Against &amp;ldquo;Purely Material&amp;rdquo; Explanations of Generation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matter is &lt;em&gt;passive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335b30&amp;ndash;34 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For, to beginwith, it is characteristic of matter to suffer
action, i.e. to be moved; but to move, i.e. to act, belongs to a
different power. This is obvious both in the things that
come-to-be by art and in those that come-to-be by nature.
Water does not of itself produce out of itself an animal; and it
is the art, not the wood, that makes a bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Omits the more controlling cause&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335b34&amp;ndash;5 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor is this their only error. They make a second mistake in omitting the more
controlling cause; for they eliminate the essential nature, i.e.
the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes &lt;em&gt;instruments&lt;/em&gt; used by the cause for the cause itself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 336a1&amp;ndash;14 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what is more, since they remove the
formal cause, they invest the forces they assign to the simple
bodies—the forces which enable these bodies to bring things
into being—with too instrumental a character. For since (as
they say) it is the nature of the hot to dissociate, of the cold to
bring together, and of each remaining [5] contrary either to
act or to suffer action, it is out of such materials and by their
agency (so they maintain) that everything else comes-to-be
and passes-away. Yet it is evident that even Fire is itself
moved, i.e. suffers action. Moreover their procedure is
virtually the same as if one were to treat the saw (and the
various instruments of [10] carpentry) as the cause of the
things that come-to-be; for the wood must be divided if a man
saws, must become smooth if he planes, and so on with the
remaining tools. Hence, however true it may be that Fire is
active, i.e. sets things moving, there is a further point they fail
to observe—viz. that Fire is inferior to the tools or
instruments in the manner in which it sets things moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;against-purely-formal-explanations-of-generation&#34;&gt;Against &amp;ldquo;Purely Formal&amp;rdquo; Explanations of Generation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socrates &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; hypothesis regarding &amp;ldquo;the cause of generation and destruction&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plato, &lt;em&gt;Phaedo&lt;/em&gt; 100d&amp;ndash;101d (Grube tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I no longer understand or recognize those other sophisticated causes,
and if someone tells me that a thing is beautiful because it has a bright
color or shape or any such thing, I ignore these other reasons—for all these
confuse me—but I simply, naively and perhaps foolishly cling to this, that
nothing else makes it beautiful other than the presence of, or the sharing
in, or however you may describe its relationship to that Beautiful we
mentioned, for I will not insist on the precise nature of the relationship,
but that all beautiful things are beautiful by the Beautiful. That, I think,
is the safest answer I can give myself or anyone else. And if I stick to this
I think I shall never fall into error. This is the safe answer for me or anyone
else to give, namely, that it is through Beauty that beautiful things are
made beautiful. Or do you not think so too?—I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then would you not avoid saying that when one is added to one it is
the addition and when it is divided it is the division that is the cause of
two? And you would loudly exclaim that you do not know how else each
thing can come to be except by sharing in the particular reality in which
it shares, and in these cases you do not know of any other cause of becoming
two except by sharing in Twoness, and that the things that are to be two
must share in this, as that which is to be one must share in Oneness, and
you would dismiss these additions and divisions and other such subtleties,
and leave them to those wiser than yourself to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objections to the view&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;intermittancy&amp;rdquo; of generation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335b18&amp;ndash;20 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if the Forms
are causes, why is their generating activity intermittent
instead of perpetual and continuous—since there always are
participants as well as Forms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;!--list-separator--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignores other causes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335b20&amp;ndash;24 (Joachim tr.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, in some instances we see [20]
that the cause is other than the Form. For it is the doctor who
implants health and the man of science who implants science,
although Health itself and Science itself are as well as the
participants; and the same principle applies to everything else
that is produced in accordance with a capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-third-principle&#34;&gt;The Third Principle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GC&lt;/em&gt; 2.9, 335a33&amp;ndash;b8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now cause, in the sense of matter, for the things which are
such as to come-to-be is that which can be and not be; and
this is identical with that which can come to be and pass
away, since the latter, while it is at one time, at another time
is not. (For whereas some things are of necessity, viz. the
eternal things, others of necessity are not. And of these two
sets of things, since they cannot diverge from the [335b1]
necessity of their nature, it is impossible for the first not to be
and impossible for the second to be. Other things, however,
can both be and not be.) Hence coming-to-be and
passing-away must occur within the field of that which can be
and not be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, therefore, is cause in the sense of matter for
the things which are such as to [5] come-to-be; while cause,
in the sense of their end, is their figure or form—and that is
the formula expressing the substance of each of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the third principle must be present as well—the cause
vaguely dreamed of by all our predecessors, definitely stated
by none of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strangely, A. does not refer to the third cause by name, but it should be clear what sort of cause A.&amp;rsquo;s objections to the &amp;ldquo;purely material&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;purely formal&amp;rdquo; accounts of change point to: &lt;strong&gt;the mover&lt;/strong&gt; (typically&amp;mdash;among perishable things&amp;mdash;the efficient cause).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
