<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Robert Howton</title>
    <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Robert Howton</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Robert Howton</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://www.roberthowton.com/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Modern Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/intro_early_modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/intro_early_modern/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dioptrique.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Feature Image&#34; title=&#34;Figures from Descartes&#39; Optics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
HAHAHUGOSHORTCODE-TOC0-HBHB
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philosophy in Western Europe underwent a dramatic shift in the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; centuries. Spurred by the ongoing revolution in science and the rediscovery of some lost works of Classical Greek and Roman philosophy, philosophers of this period turned away from the scholastic disputes practiced in the universities of Europe to a whole new set of philosophical questions, including: What am I? How do I relate to my body? Is knowledge possible? If so, where does it come from? For proponents of this new approach to philosophy, exploration of these questions did not require extensive education or training, only the exercise of one&amp;rsquo;s inborn rational faculties. For this reason, philosophy in this period also witnessed another revolution: the increasing influence of women philosophers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will introduce you to the major questions and figures of 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century philosophy in Western Europe. We begin with René Descartes, arguably the most important thinker of the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. Descartes&amp;rsquo; philosophical work posed the questions with which subsequent philosophers would wrestle. After looking at Descartes&amp;rsquo; answers to these questions, we&amp;rsquo;ll turn to those of his contemporaries and successors, including Malebranche, Cavendish, Leibniz, Berkeley, Locke, and Hume. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll close our survey with a look at the most important philosopher of the 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century: Immanuel Kant, whose transcendental philosophy represents the culmination of Descartes&amp;rsquo; philosophical legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will emphasize close reading, analysis, and evaluation of basic philosophical works from the early modern period, with the aim of establishing a broad understanding of the philosophical controversies of that period and cultivating the skills necessary for appreciating these and other topics in philosophy. The successful student will demonstrate the ability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to state and articulate, verbally and in writing, philosophical ideas and questions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to read and critically assess philosophical literature,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to identify the elements of an argument and assess it for soundness and validity, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to apply these skills to novel cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to success in this course is to keep up with the assigned readings and to attend and participate regularly in class activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    If you keep up with the lectures and readings you will not be assigned anything for which you are unprepared!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-components&#34;&gt;Course Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two basic components of this course, &lt;strong&gt;lectures&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;class discussion&lt;/strong&gt;. Both components are mandatory, and both are moreover crucial for your success in this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lectures&#34;&gt;Lectures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of my lectures is to introduce you to the theories, concepts, and problems that make up the content of the course. These lectures will be accompanied by slide-show presentations, which I will share with you to use outside of lecture as a guide to reading the assigned texts. Hence, &lt;strong&gt;you will not be expected to come to the lecture having read the material assigned for that day&lt;/strong&gt;, but you will be expected to have read the material prior to class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;class-discussion&#34;&gt;Class Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philosophy is a &lt;em&gt;discursive&lt;/em&gt; enterprise: progress in understanding and evaluating philosophical ideas is most effectively made through interpersonal discussion, where you can test, correct, and improve your understanding of those ideas. To help you engage with philosophical ideas in this way, we will meet periodically for  general class discussion of the topics recently introduced in the lecture. Upon arrival at these meetings, students will complete a short &lt;strong&gt;reading reflection&lt;/strong&gt; on the texts assigned for that meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will be expected to write two &lt;strong&gt;term tests&lt;/strong&gt; and two &lt;strong&gt;term papers&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as satisfy requirements for satisfactory &lt;strong&gt;participation&lt;/strong&gt; in lectures and discussion meetings. With the exception of University excused absences, which must be supported by official documentation, students are expected to attend all other lectures and discussion meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assignments&#34;&gt;Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final grades will be determined according to the following rubric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Assignment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Percentage of Final Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Paper 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Paper 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Test 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Test 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    You must complete &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; assignments in order to pass the course!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;grading-scale&#34;&gt;Grading Scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Score&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;96&amp;ndash;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surpasses All Grading Criteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90&amp;ndash;95&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; No Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87&amp;ndash;89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; At Least One Minor Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83&amp;ndash;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Minor Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&amp;ndash;82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Perhaps Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77&amp;ndash;79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; One or More Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&amp;ndash;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70&amp;ndash;72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Several Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67&amp;ndash;69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Many Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64&amp;ndash;66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; At Least One Fatal Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60&amp;ndash;63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; One or More Fatal Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&amp;ndash;59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies No Grading Criteria, Incomplete, or Plagiarized&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;texts-course-materials&#34;&gt;Texts &amp;amp; Course Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-texts&#34;&gt;Required Texts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two required texts for this course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ariew, Roger and Eric Watkins, eds. &lt;em&gt;Modern Philosophy: an Anthology of Primary Sources&lt;/em&gt;, 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; ed. Indianapolis, Ind: Hackett Pub. Co, 2009.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atherton, Margaret. &lt;em&gt;Women Philosophers of the Early Modern Period&lt;/em&gt;. Indianapolis: Hackett Pub. Co, 1994.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are available at Pandora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-materials&#34;&gt;Additional Materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students looking for additional study materials are encouraged to consult the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plato.stanford.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. I am also compiling a playlist of YouTube videos related to modern philosophy; there is a link to it on Blackboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-policies&#34;&gt;Course Policies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disabilities-and-different-styles-of-learning&#34;&gt;Disabilities and Different Styles of Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education is a pluralistic enterprise: there are several and often incompatible styles of learning. If you believe there is an alternative approach to this material that would better suit your style of learning, do not hesitate to bring it up with me. If you have a disability for which you are or may be requesting accommodation, you are encouraged to contact both me and the Office of Disability Services at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+90(212)3381042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0 (212) 338 10 42&lt;/a&gt; as early as possible in the term. ODS will verify your disability and determine reasonable accommodations for this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-honesty&#34;&gt;Academic Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this course is to promote and assess &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; satisfaction of the above-stated course objectives. Cheating not plagiarism will not be tolerated. Students suspected of violating the University&amp;rsquo;s policy on academic integrity, noted below, will be required to participate in the required procedural process as initiated by the instructor. A minimum sanction of a zero score for the quiz, exam, or paper will be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Be sure you are familiar with KU&amp;rsquo;s complete policy on academic honesty, which is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-policy&#34;&gt;Email Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me two business days to respond to emails. Please do not email me with questions of philosophical substance&amp;mdash;that is what lecture, discussion, and office hours are for&amp;mdash;and please consult this syllabus before asking questions about course policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;important-links&#34;&gt;Important Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#stdrights&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Rights &amp;amp; Responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/grievance-procedures/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Grievance Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Classroom Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusion: When Appearances Deceive</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/illusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/illusion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bayer3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Feature Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
HAHAHUGOSHORTCODE-TOC0-HBHB
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think we see the world around us as it is. Sometimes, however, things are not as they appear. We see a straight stick in the water as bent, or are taken in by a vivid dream or hallucination, or treat as reliable a source that turns out to peddle fake news. How do these various illusions impact our efforts to learn from experience? What strategies can we adopt&amp;mdash;as individuals, as researchers, and as citizens&amp;mdash;to combat these sorts of error? And what happens when things go right, when our senses teach us how the world really is? This course will explore these and similar questions concerning illusions in their many forms, drawing on resources past and present from philosophy, psychology, neuroscience, and the sociology of science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course aims to help students:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain an appreciation for the various forms perceptual error and their significance for our cognitive lives;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come to understand the cultural and historical influences shaping our notions of illusion, perception, and reality; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think freely and critically about how these issues affect them as individuals, researchers, and citizens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the course, the successful student will have demonstrated the ability to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;express philosophical ideas clearly, both verbally and in writing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read and critically assess philosophical and other academic literature;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify the elements of an argument and assess it for soundness and validity; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apply these skills to novel cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to success in this course is to keep up with the assigned readings and to attend and participate regularly in class activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    If you keep up with the lectures and readings you will not be assigned anything for which you are unprepared!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-components&#34;&gt;Course Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each student&amp;rsquo;s success in meeting these objectives will be assessed on the following bases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will be expected to write &lt;strong&gt;two term tests&lt;/strong&gt; covering the major ideas presented in class, as well as &lt;strong&gt;two term papers&lt;/strong&gt; responding in-depth to questions prompted by course readings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionaly, student attendance and class participation will be assessed on the basis of &lt;strong&gt;reading response questions&lt;/strong&gt;. Questions will be posted to Blackboard at the start of each Unit and will be due by midnight before the third and final meeting of the Unit, which will be devoted to in-depth discussion of course readings. (Students may opt out of reading responses with no penalty only &lt;em&gt;once&lt;/em&gt;; with the exception of University excused absences, which must be supported by official documentation, students must complete &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; other reading responses and attend all other class meetings.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, on discussion days students will be assessed for their &lt;strong&gt;participation&lt;/strong&gt; in class discussion and group activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final grades will be determined according to the following rubrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assignment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of Final Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Paper 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Paper 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Test 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Term Test 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    You must complete &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; assignments in order to pass the course!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;grading-scale&#34;&gt;Grading Scale&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Score&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;96&amp;ndash;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surpasses All Grading Criteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90&amp;ndash;95&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; No Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87&amp;ndash;89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; At Least One Minor Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83&amp;ndash;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Minor Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&amp;ndash;82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Perhaps Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77&amp;ndash;79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; One or More Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&amp;ndash;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70&amp;ndash;72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Several Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67&amp;ndash;69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Many Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64&amp;ndash;66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; At Least One Fatal Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60&amp;ndash;63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; One or More Fatal Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&amp;ndash;59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies No Grading Criteria, Incomplete, or Plagiarized&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Final grades are rounded up from the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; decimal place; no exceptions will be made.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;texts-course-materials&#34;&gt;Texts &amp;amp; Course Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-texts&#34;&gt;Required Texts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no required texts for this course. All required readings will be posted to Blackboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-materials&#34;&gt;Additional Materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students looking for additional study materials are encouraged to consult the &lt;a href=&#34;plato.stanford.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-policies&#34;&gt;Course Policies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disabilities-and-different-styles-of-learning&#34;&gt;Disabilities and Different Styles of Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education is a pluralistic enterprise: there are several and often incompatible styles of learning. If you believe there is an alternative approach to this material that would better suit your style of learning, do not hesitate to bring it up with me. If you have a disability for which you are or may be requesting accommodation, you are encouraged to contact both me and the Office of Disability Services at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+90(212)3381042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0 (212) 338 10 42&lt;/a&gt; as early as possible in the term. ODS will verify your disability and determine reasonable accommodations for this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-honesty&#34;&gt;Academic Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this course is to promote and assess &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; satisfaction of the above-stated course objectives. Cheating not plagiarism will not be tolerated. Students suspected of violating the University&amp;rsquo;s policy on academic integrity, noted below, will be required to participate in the required procedural process as initiated by the instructor. A minimum sanction of a zero score for the quiz, exam, or paper will be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Be sure you are familiar with KU&amp;rsquo;s complete policy on academic honesty, which is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-policy&#34;&gt;Email Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me two business days to respond to emails. Please do not email me with questions of philosophical substance&amp;mdash;that is what lecture, discussion, and office hours are for&amp;mdash;and please consult this syllabus before asking questions about course policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;important-links&#34;&gt;Important Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#stdrights&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Rights &amp;amp; Responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/grievance-procedures/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Grievance Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Classroom Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of the Criterion</title>
      <link>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/the_problem_of_the_criterion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 10:23:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.roberthowton.com/course/the_problem_of_the_criterion/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;homomensura2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Feature Image&#34; title=&#34;An version of the &#39;Vetruvian Man&#39; inspired by Protagoras&#39; homo mensura doctrine&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
HAHAHUGOSHORTCODE-TOC0-HBHB
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is knowledge possible for us, and if so, how? For many epistemologists, both ancient and modern, whether and how knowledge is attainable depends on whether we possess some criterion or standard by which to judge what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the case from what merely &lt;em&gt;appears&lt;/em&gt; to be the case. This idea, that knowledge requires a &lt;em&gt;criterion of truth&lt;/em&gt;, has its origins in antiquity, in Hellenistic debates between so-called Dogmatists and Skeptics about whether human beings possess&amp;mdash;or can ever possess&amp;mdash;such a criterion. Our aim in this course will be to explore the ancient roots of this &amp;ldquo;problem of the criterion&amp;rdquo;, in order to gain a better understanding of the various arguments and positions of the dogmatic and skeptical Hellenistic schools, as well as the prehistory of this debate in Hellenic figures such as Protagoras, Democritus, and, more controversially, Plato and Aristotle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course aims to establish a broad understanding of core issues in ancient epistemology and to develop the skills necessary for appreciating these and other issues in ancient and contemporary philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The successful student will demonstrate the ability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to state and articulate, verbally and in writing, major ideas and controversies related to ancient epistemology,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to read and critically assess relevant primary and secondary literature,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to apply these skills to novel cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    If you keep up with the lectures and readings you will not be assigned anything for which you are unprepared!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-components&#34;&gt;Course Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students&amp;rsquo; success in meeting these course goals will be evaluated on the following bases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Undergraduate students&lt;/strong&gt; will be expected to write &lt;strong&gt;two passage commentaries&lt;/strong&gt;. The commentaries are designed to stimulate in-depth historical and philosophical engagement with one of the major passages discussed in class and relevant secondary literature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graduate students&lt;/strong&gt; will be expected to write &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt; a &lt;strong&gt;passage commentary&lt;/strong&gt; and a 12&amp;ndash;15 page &lt;strong&gt;final paper&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; a 20 page &lt;strong&gt;final paper&lt;/strong&gt;. The final paper will address a substantive interpretive issue concerning Hellenistic epistemology and/or related philosophical issues. Topics and secondary literature will be selected in consultation with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Class participation will be evaluated on the basis of the student&amp;rsquo;s answer to periodic &lt;strong&gt;reading response questions&lt;/strong&gt;, which will be distributed in advance and must be turned in prior to the start of the meeting in which the relevant reading is to be discussed. (Students may opt out of reading responses with no penalty a maximum of &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; times; students who do not opt out of three reading responses may use these to replace lower-scoring responses; with the exception of University excused absences, which must be supported by official documentation, students must complete all other reading responses and attend all other class meetings.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, students will give at least one 10&amp;ndash;15 minute &lt;strong&gt;in-class presentation&lt;/strong&gt;. Presentation topics and secondary literature will be selected in consultation with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evaluation&#34;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final grades will be determined according to the following rubrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;undergraduate-students&#34;&gt;Undergraduate Students&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assignment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of Final Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commentary 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commentary 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;35%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graduate-students&#34;&gt;Graduate Students&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assignment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of Final Grade (Option 1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of Final Grade (Option 2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commentary&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Final Paper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;35%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Participation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    You must complete &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; assignments in order to pass the course!
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;grading-scale&#34;&gt;Grading Scale&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Score&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;96&amp;ndash;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Surpasses All Grading Criteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90&amp;ndash;95&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; No Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;87&amp;ndash;89&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies All Grading Criteria; At Least One Minor Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;83&amp;ndash;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Minor Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&amp;ndash;82&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; Perhaps Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;77&amp;ndash;79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Most Grading Criteria; One or More Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;73&amp;ndash;76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Some Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70&amp;ndash;72&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Several Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;67&amp;ndash;69&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Some Grading Criteria; Many Major Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;64&amp;ndash;66&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; At Least One Fatal Error&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60&amp;ndash;63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies Almost No Grading Criteria; One or More Fatal Errors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&amp;ndash;59&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfies No Grading Criteria, Incomplete, or Plagiarized&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Final grades are rounded up from the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; decimal place; no exceptions will be made.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;texts-course-materials&#34;&gt;Texts &amp;amp; Course Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-texts&#34;&gt;Required Texts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one required text for the course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brittain, Charles (ed.). 2006. &lt;em&gt;Cicero: On Academic Scepticism&lt;/em&gt;. Indianapolis, IN: Hackett Publishing Co.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is available at Pandora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-materials&#34;&gt;Additional Materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional readings will be posted to Blackboard. Scholarship on ancient epistemology since the late 20^th^ century has been for the most part excellent. Students seeking additional resources are encouraged to consult the bibliographies included with relevant entries in the &lt;a href=&#34;plato.stanford.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stanford Enclyclopedia of Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the following resources, which are on hold at the library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algra, Keimpe, ed. 1999. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge History of Hellenistic Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schofield, Malcolm, Myles Burnyeat, and Jonathan Barnes, eds. 1980. &lt;em&gt;Doubt and Dogmatism: Studies in Hellenistic Epistemology&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford: Clarendon Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annas, Julia and Jonathan Barnes (eds.). 2000. &lt;em&gt;Sextus Empiricus: Outlines of Scepticism&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bett, Richard, ed. 2005. &lt;em&gt;Sextus Empiricus: Against the Logicians&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-policies&#34;&gt;Course Policies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disabilities-and-different-styles-of-learning&#34;&gt;Disabilities and Different Styles of Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education is a pluralistic enterprise: there are several and often incompatible styles of learning. If you believe there is an alternative approach to this material that would better suit your style of learning, do not hesitate to bring it up with me. If you have a disability for which you are or may be requesting accommodation, you are encouraged to contact both me and the Office of Disability Services at &lt;a href=&#34;tel:+90(212)3381042&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0 (212) 338 10 42&lt;/a&gt; as early as possible in the term. ODS will verify your disability and determine reasonable accommodations for this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-honesty&#34;&gt;Academic Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this course is to promote and assess &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; satisfaction of the above-stated course objectives. Cheating not plagiarism will not be tolerated. Students suspected of violating the University&amp;rsquo;s policy on academic integrity, noted below, will be required to participate in the required procedural process as initiated by the instructor. A minimum sanction of a zero score for the quiz, exam, or paper will be imposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Be sure you are familiar with KU&amp;rsquo;s complete policy on academic honesty, which is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;email-policy&#34;&gt;Email Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me two business days to respond to emails. Please do not email me with questions of philosophical substance&amp;mdash;that is what lecture, discussion, and office hours are for&amp;mdash;and please consult this syllabus before asking questions about course policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;important-links&#34;&gt;Important Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct#stdrights&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Rights &amp;amp; Responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/grievance-procedures/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic Grievance Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vpaa.ku.edu.tr/academic/student-code-of-conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Classroom Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
